<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Games on David Saltares</title>
    <link>https://saltares.dev/games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Games on David Saltares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saltares.dev/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Doodle</title>
      <link>https://saltares.dev/games/doodle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.dev/games/doodle/</guid>
      <description>✏️ Doodle is a crazy drawing &amp;amp; guessing chain game. Think Pictionary meets Telephone. Get on a video call with friends and give it a try. It&amp;rsquo;s completely free and has no ads.
🦠 I made it a side project during covid-19 confinement to be played during covid-19 confinement.
📸 Screenshots Ewnn nsr u0 aax0 ve
Ewnn t4k u8 aets86
Brainstorming
Covid19
Flintstones
💻 Technical details Doodle is open source under the MIT license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Maze</title>
      <link>https://saltares.dev/games/math-maze/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 17:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.dev/games/math-maze/</guid>
      <description>Is your head agile enough to succeed at this math based brain teaser game? Reach the exit of the labyrinth as fast as you can by using operations that will open the conditional blockages. Freshen up your mental calculus without even realising!
Role: designer, coder and artist Year: 2013 Development time: 5 months (after work!) Technology: Java language using libgdx Links: source, Facebook Trailer Screenshots Math maze 01
Math maze 02</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freegemas Libgdx</title>
      <link>https://saltares.dev/games/freegemas-for-android-and-html5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 21:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.dev/games/freegemas-for-android-and-html5/</guid>
      <description>Fregemas libgdx is a Java port of the original game developed by José Tomás Tocino. It’s a simple but addictive puzzle game where the player has to swap gems to make groups of three or more adjacent ones.
Role: port programmer, UI redesign Year: 2012 Development time: 2 weeks Technology: Java language using libgdx Download: Freegemas desktop, Freegemas Android, source code Original version Screenshots Freegemas 01
Freegemas 02
Freegemas 03</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban Race</title>
      <link>https://saltares.dev/games/urban-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 19:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.dev/games/urban-race/</guid>
      <description> urbanrace Urban Race is an open source 3D time attack racing game for Windows. It was a university project for which I had to learn both C# and XNA.
Role: game designer, artist and sole programmer. Year: 2011 Development time: 1 month Technology: C# language using XNA Game Studio 4.0 Download: Urban Race 1.0, source code Screenshots Urbanrace 1
Urbanrace 2
Urbanrace 3
Urbanrace 4
Urbanrace 5
Features 3 different tracks Beat your own record Blender level creation Simple car physics Collision detection Terrain Realistic car engine sound Video </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sion Tower</title>
      <link>https://saltares.dev/games/sion-tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 22:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.dev/games/sion-tower/</guid>
      <description>Open source multiplatform tactical action 3D game in which the player controls a young magician who has to defend the Sacred Tower from an enemy invasion.
It was my final degree project and it won the V Open Source University Contest, a national competition in Spain between university students.
Role: project leader, game designer, sole programmer and level designer. Year: 2011 Development time: 6 months Team: 1 3D artist, 1 2D artist, 2 musicians and 1 sfx artist Technology: C++ language using Ogre3D, OIS, MyGUI and SDL Download: source code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IberOgre</title>
      <link>https://saltares.dev/games/iberogre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 19:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.dev/games/iberogre/</guid>
      <description>Ogre 3D games programming wiki in Spanish language. It was part of my final degree project with Sion Tower.
Role: designer, writer and samples programmer Year: 2011 Development time: 6 months Technology: C++ language using Ogre3D and Mediawiki engine Sample Code: GitHub Features Geometry and math articles. Ogre articles. Complementary technology articles: OIS, Blender, Bullet. Samples of increasing complexity discussed in detail. Use of open source tools. Good practices to develop cross platform software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granny&#39;s Bloodbath</title>
      <link>https://saltares.dev/games/grannys-bloodbath/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 19:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.dev/games/grannys-bloodbath/</guid>
      <description>grannysbloodbath Open source side scrolling platform action game in which the player controls a peaceful grandma who gets really angry when a horde of zombies disturbs her. It’s a university project developed in a team of three.
Role: game designer, lead programmer, 2D artist and level designer Year: 2010 Development time: 3 months Team: 2 additional programmers Technology: C++ language using SDL Download: Granny’s Bloodbath 0.5 (Windows), Granny’s Bloodbath 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Force Pilot</title>
      <link>https://saltares.dev/games/air-force-pilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 19:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.dev/games/air-force-pilot/</guid>
      <description>airforcepilot-banner Top view 2D plane shooter in which the player controls a fighter who has to knock down enemy planes in the level. It was my first game and it was finalist in an open source contest in Cádiz University (Spain).
Role: game designer, sole programmer and artist Year: 2009 Development time: 2 months Technology: C++ language using SDL Download: source code Screenshots Airforcepilot 1
Airforcepilot 2
Airforcepilot 3</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
