<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Saltares</title>
    <link>https://saltares.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on David Saltares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saltares.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The David Test - An updated Joel Test for 2022</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/the-david-test-an-updated-joel-test-for-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/the-david-test-an-updated-joel-test-for-2022/</guid>
      <description>The famous Joel Test is a super quick and fun way to evaluate an engineering organisation by answering 12 simple &amp;ldquo;yes or no&amp;rdquo; questions. At the end, you get a score over 12. There is a problem however.
The test is now 22 years old 😱.
Tools and processes to build software have changed a fair bit over the last two decades. What was considered a potential nice to have, may have become an absolute basic.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;The famous &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2000/08/09/the-joel-test-12-steps-to-better-code/&#34;&gt;Joel Test&lt;/a&gt; is a super quick and fun way to evaluate an engineering organisation by answering 12 simple &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;yes or no&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; questions. At the end, you get a score over 12. There is a problem however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test is now 22 years old 😱.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools and processes to build software have changed a fair bit over the last two decades. What was considered a potential nice to have, may have become an absolute basic. So, I decided to come up with my own, updated test. Make sure to read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2000/08/09/the-joel-test-12-steps-to-better-code/&#34;&gt;the original one&lt;/a&gt; first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behold the &lt;strong&gt;David Test&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can new joiners set up and run the system locally in less than one day by just reading the docs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are your builds made without any human intervention?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you automatically deploy to production?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the system, to some degree, observable?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you have a technical debt strategy you actually follow?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is your team predictable?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the squad (Engineering + PM + Design) refine the backlog together?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do engineers have sizeable chunks of time free of meetings?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can engineers choose the best tools for the job?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the team collectively own quality and have a testing strategy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you have a standardized interview process?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you have a continuous discovery culture?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive a bit deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1--can-new-joiners-set-up-and-run-the-system-locally-in-less-than-one-day-by-just-reading-the-docs&#34;&gt;1. 👩‍💻 Can new joiners set up and run the system locally in less than one day by just reading the docs?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies that do not have a simple and well documented environment setup process suffer all sorts of issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a new engineer joins, they spend forever before they can even think of contributing with a code change. As the process is not documented, they get blocked constantly. Multiple people need to help, as knowledge is spread across. As a result, the new joiner is frustrated from day 1!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more insidious consequence is the myriad of subtle issues different members of the team experience over time as everyone has environments configured in significantly different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, a new engineer should follow the documentation and bring up the application locally within 30 minutes max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2--are-your-production-builds-made-without-any-human-intervention&#34;&gt;2. 🚚 Are your production builds made without any human intervention?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many companies still rely on developers making production builds on their local machines to ship changes. Not only does this take time, it also introduces a silly amount of risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once caused a major outage after some local changes made it into a build that got deployed 🙈. I am deeply embarrassed but it&amp;rsquo;s very much a real story and the best example I can give to illustrate this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let machines make the builds in reproducible environments with no human intervention at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3--do-you-automatically-deploy-to-production&#34;&gt;3. 🚢 Do you automatically deploy to production?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When teams deploy to production after every merge to the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch something magical happens. The size of every deployment becomes smaller and the feedback loop tightens. The consequences are fantastic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes are smaller, the risk of a change breaking the system is reduced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a breaking change is introduced, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to identify it and fix it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of integrating code becomes tiny.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very least, teams should routinely deploy to production multiple times a week. Ideally, there should be multiple deployments to production a day, one for every merge to &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rule is &lt;a href=&#34;https://charity.wtf/2021/02/19/how-much-is-your-fear-costing-you/&#34;&gt;15 minutes or bust&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4--is-the-system-to-some-degree-observable&#34;&gt;4. 🌡️ Is the system, to some degree, observable?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observability has many facets and folks often misunderstand what it means. Essentially, can you answer questions about the state of our system and what real users are experiencing just by looking at its outputs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very least, some of the following need to be present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alerting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracing is, perhaps, the most advanced, so you get a pass if you don&amp;rsquo;t have it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5--do-you-have-a-technical-debt-strategy-you-actually-follow&#34;&gt;5. 🏦 Do you have a technical debt strategy you actually follow?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too much technical debt can slow you down to a crawl. At the same time, &lt;a href=&#34;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebtQuadrant.html&#34;&gt;no technical debt at all is also bad&lt;/a&gt;! Engineering orgs should have a strategy outlining their approach to technical debt and actually follow it. This often requires strong relationships of trust and alignment with other roles within Product such as Product Managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not having a strategy means that tech debt is tackled in a chaotic, unstructured way, thus limiting the impact. Perhaps, tech debt is not even tackled at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6--is-your-team-predictable&#34;&gt;6. 📊 Is your team predictable?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/why-estimating-is-so-damn-hard-d0f945f30185&#34;&gt;Estimates are damn hard&lt;/a&gt; but the reality is that businesses need to know approximately when projects will be done, contracts may depend on them! A team that seldom misses deadlines in a sustainable way is one that builds a tremendous amount of trust. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the key indicators of high performing teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be able to predict everything with high precision. In order to be predictable, you must break down projects into tiny increments. These tiny increments are a lot easier to predict. If you continuously deploy your incomplete increments behind feature flags, the chances of having something releasable when time runs out are much higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;7--does-the-squad-engineering--pm--design-refine-the-backlog-together&#34;&gt;7. 👌 Does the squad (Engineering + PM + Design) refine the backlog together?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too often does one see teams where it&amp;rsquo;s just the lead and the PM who refine the backlog. Then, the lead breaks stories into tasks and assigns them to the team. That is a horrendous practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not everyone will be aligned on what the team is making and why. People will make worse decisions during implementation, resulting in more back and forth or the wrong thing gets built.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a diverse set of people who feel safe to contribute refine together, you will inevitably &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2016/11/why-diverse-teams-are-smarter&#34;&gt;build a better product&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individuals will never learn how to break down a larger story into smaller chunks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People lose agency over the work they do and become disengaged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;8--do-engineers-have-sizeable-chunks-of-time-free-of-meetings&#34;&gt;8. 🤔 Do engineers have sizeable chunks of time free of meetings?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote work has become more mainstream and many folks no longer need to deal with noisy open plan offices. However, that does not mean they are free to do deep work for large chunks of time because their calendars may be full with a collection of Zoom calls spread across the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everybody is different, but most people are more productive when they can block out time for deep, uninterrupted work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;9--can-engineers-choose-the-best-tools-for-the-job&#34;&gt;9. 🛠️ Can engineers choose the best tools for the job?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to get the best tools money can buy is crucial. Engineers are expensive and you don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay them so that they can spend endless hours fighting their tools or doing work that could easily be automated by an off the shelf product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can take this forward and say that there isn&amp;rsquo;t a single toolbox to fit them all. People may feel more comfortable with a particular IDE and they should have the freedom to not have to rewire their brain in order to become proficient with another one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;10--does-the-team-collectively-own-quality-and-have-a-testing-strategy&#34;&gt;10. 🐛 Does the team collectively own quality and have a testing strategy?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, teams that cared about quality simply had a separate QA department. I think that dilutes the ownership of quality in product delivery teams. In my experience, quality is higher when the whole cross-functional squad cares about it and owns it. You may still have a QA role, but they should be embedded within the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It certainly helps when a testing strategy exists, it&amp;rsquo;s documented and actually applied. This document should outline the principles for automated and manual testing ans well as figuring out what to test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;11--do-you-have-a-standardized-interview-process&#34;&gt;11. 💬 Do you have a standardized interview process?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step an organisation can take to avoid having a completely &lt;a href=&#34;https://betterprogramming.pub/the-software-engineering-hiring-process-is-broken-and-exclusionary-1632cc5a030c&#34;&gt;broken interview process&lt;/a&gt; is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://themanagershandbook.com/hiring-and-onboarding/hiring-101&#34;&gt;standardize it&lt;/a&gt;. An established process everyone goes through allows you to compare candidates more effectively while minimizing bias. It will become slightly easier to increase the diversity of the team, although it &lt;a href=&#34;https://lauratacho.medium.com/recruiting-more-underrepresented-candidates-wont-magically-make-your-organisation-inclusive-96651c6fb4b8&#34;&gt;won&amp;rsquo;t magically make your team more inclusive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A standard process is the absolute bare minimum. Do you want to work at a place where only buddies are hired, everyone thinks the same and it&amp;rsquo;s basically a group of techbros?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;12--do-you-have-a-continuous-discovery-culture&#34;&gt;12. 🔍 Do you have a continuous discovery culture?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iterative process does not only apply to actually delivering the software, it&amp;rsquo;s extremely relevant within discovery as well. Organisations that continuously learn about users, test for product market fit and analyse the usage of the most recently released feature will always have the upper hand. When folks other than the PM and designer are involved, the team is set up for success. Look at whether, as an engineer, you can actively participate in the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User interviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design sprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A/B testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-what-is-your-organisations-score&#34;&gt;✅ What is your organisation&amp;rsquo;s score?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12/12 is ideal. 10/12 is ok, it&amp;rsquo;s always good to aspire to do better! Anything below it and you should start making some changes, NOW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🙌 Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote work panel at UOC (Spanish)</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/remote-work-panel-at-uoc-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/remote-work-panel-at-uoc-spanish/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s already been a while but, back in November last year, I participated in a panel about remote work organised by the Universitat Oberta de Catalunya (UOC). It was fantastic to share thoughts and opinions with other folks that had different backgrounds and experiences.
📽️ You can watch the entire session here although it is in Spanish.
  </description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s already been a while but, back in November last year, I participated in a panel about remote work organised by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uoc.edu/portal/en/index.html&#34;&gt;Universitat Oberta de Catalunya (UOC)&lt;/a&gt;. It was fantastic to share thoughts and opinions with other folks that had different backgrounds and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📽️ You can watch the entire session here although it is in Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div
  style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 62.5%; height: 0; margin-bottom: 1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe
    style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34;
    src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tEUE3VjcDN0&#34;
    frameborder=&#34;0&#34;
    allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34;
    allowfullscreen
  &gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticky nav bar on scroll with React hooks</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/sticky-nav-bar-on-scroll-with-react-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/sticky-nav-bar-on-scroll-with-react-hooks/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I built a small React application that had a header, a navigation bar underneath and then the content. After scrolling past the header, the navigation bar was supposed to stay at the top and not scroll away.
Like so.
 Making the navigation bar position: fixed; top 0; was not going to cut it because the header had to come first unless we scrolled past the navigation bar.
I wanted to keep the component that controls the layout as simple as possible, so I abstracted the stickiness logic into a useSticky hook.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I built a small React application that had a header, a navigation bar underneath and then the content. After scrolling past the header, the navigation bar was supposed to stay at the top and not scroll away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe
  src=&#34;https://codesandbox.io/embed/sticky-scrolling-header-vwsso?fontsize=14&amp;hidenavigation=1&amp;theme=dark&amp;view=preview&#34;
  style=&#34;width:100%; height:500px; border:1px solid #000; border-radius: 4px; overflow:hidden;&#34;
  title=&#34;sticky-scrolling-header&#34;
  allow=&#34;accelerometer; ambient-light-sensor; camera; encrypted-media; geolocation; gyroscope; hid; microphone; midi; payment; usb; vr; xr-spatial-tracking&#34;
  sandbox=&#34;allow-forms allow-modals allow-popups allow-presentation allow-same-origin allow-scripts&#34;
  &gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the navigation bar &lt;code&gt;position: fixed; top 0;&lt;/code&gt; was not going to cut it because the header had to come first unless we scrolled past the navigation bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to keep the component that controls the layout as simple as possible, so I abstracted the stickiness logic into a &lt;code&gt;useSticky&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html&#34;&gt;hook&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;d use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-jsx&#34; data-lang=&#34;jsx&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;classNames&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;classnames&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useSticky&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;./useSticky&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;App&lt;/span&gt;() {
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;sticky&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;stickyRef&lt;/span&gt; } &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useSticky&lt;/span&gt;();
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; (
    &amp;lt;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;header&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;header&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Header&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;header&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;nav&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;ref&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;{&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;stickyRef&lt;/span&gt;}
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;{&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;classNames&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;nav&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, { &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;sticky&lt;/span&gt; })}
      &amp;gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Sticky&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;nav&lt;/span&gt;
      &amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;nav&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;style&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;{{
          &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;sticky&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;stickyRef&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;clientHeight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;px`&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;0px&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
        }}
      /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;content&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/&amp;gt;
  );
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You stick (no pun intended) the &lt;code&gt;stickyRef&lt;/code&gt; into the thing that you want to fix to the top after you scroll past it. Then, &lt;code&gt;sticky&lt;/code&gt; will indicate whether it should be fixed at the top or not. I then use that to apply a &lt;code&gt;sticky&lt;/code&gt; class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;sticky&lt;/span&gt; {
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;position&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;fixed&lt;/span&gt;;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;top&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The extra &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt; below the &lt;code&gt;nav&lt;/code&gt; adds some extra padding so that the content does not immediately jump below the navigation bar when this becomes fixed at the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌟 The magic happens in the &lt;code&gt;useSticky&lt;/code&gt; hook itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34; data-lang=&#34;js&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useEffect&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useRef&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useState&lt;/span&gt; } &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;react&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useSticky&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; () =&amp;gt; {
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;stickyRef&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useRef&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;);
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;sticky&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;setSticky&lt;/span&gt;] &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useState&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;);
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;offset&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;setOffset&lt;/span&gt;] &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useState&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;);

  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useEffect&lt;/span&gt;(() =&amp;gt; {
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;stickyRef&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt;) {
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;;
    }
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;setOffset&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;stickyRef&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;offsetTop&lt;/span&gt;);
  }, [&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;stickyRef&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;setOffset&lt;/span&gt;]);

  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useEffect&lt;/span&gt;(() =&amp;gt; {
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;handleScroll&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; () =&amp;gt; {
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;stickyRef&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt;) {
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;;
      }

      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;setSticky&lt;/span&gt;(window.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;scrollY&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;offset&lt;/span&gt;);
    };
    window.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addEventListener&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;scroll&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;handleScroll&lt;/span&gt;);
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; () =&amp;gt; window.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;removeEventListener&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;scroll&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;handleScroll&lt;/span&gt;);
  }, [&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;setSticky&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;stickyRef&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;offset&lt;/span&gt;]);
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;stickyRef&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;sticky&lt;/span&gt; };
};

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;useSticky&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first effect measures the vertical offset of the element we want to fix at the top after it&amp;rsquo;s scrolled past. The second one listens to the &lt;code&gt;scroll&lt;/code&gt; event and determines whether we have scrolled past the element&amp;rsquo;s top edge and it needs to become sticky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🙌 Hope this is useful!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve your NextAuth.js app local development experience with a dockerized SMTP server</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/improve-your-nextauth.js-app-local-development-experience-with-a-dockerized-smtp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/improve-your-nextauth.js-app-local-development-experience-with-a-dockerized-smtp-server/</guid>
      <description>NextAuth.js makes it shockingly easy to add authentication to Next.js apps. It&amp;rsquo;s free, open source, it lets you own your data and it supports a ton of identity providers, including one time passwords or &amp;ldquo;magic links&amp;rdquo;.
Working with NextAuth.js is trivial, it sounds too good to be true!
Of course, there is a catch&amp;hellip;
The developer experience worsens because you now need a network connection to log into your locally running app, even if your database is also local.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./img/nextjs/nextauth.png&#34; alt=&#34;NextAuth.js logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://next-auth.js.org/&#34;&gt;NextAuth.js&lt;/a&gt; makes it shockingly easy to add authentication to &lt;a href=&#34;https://nextjs.org/&#34;&gt;Next.js&lt;/a&gt; apps. It&amp;rsquo;s free, open source, it lets you own your data and it supports a ton of identity providers, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One-time_password&#34;&gt;one time passwords&lt;/a&gt; or &amp;ldquo;magic links&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with NextAuth.js is trivial, it sounds too good to be true!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there is a catch&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developer experience worsens because you now need a network connection to log into your locally running app, even if your database is also local. Bye bye to chill sessions of working on the train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can fix that with a local SMTP server! Let&amp;rsquo;s see how we can set it up. I will be showing code samples, but you can find a full working example of this post &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dsaltares/saltares-blog-examples/tree/main/nextauth-mailhog&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-set-up-nextauthjs-with-the-emailprovider&#34;&gt;🔐 Set up NextAuth.js with the &lt;code&gt;EmailProvider&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s assume you already have a Next.js application. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have NextAuth.js configured, the first thing is to follow the tutorial on their landing page. Then, set the &lt;code&gt;EmailProvider&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;/pages/api/auth/[...nextauth].js&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ts&#34; data-lang=&#34;ts&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;NextAuth&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;next-auth&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;EmailProvider&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;next-auth/providers/email&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;NextAuth&lt;/span&gt;({
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;providers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;EmailProvider&lt;/span&gt;({
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;server&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;host&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;process.env.EMAIL_SERVER_HOST&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;process.env.EMAIL_SERVER_PORT&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;auth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
          &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;process.env.EMAIL_SERVER_USER&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;pass&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;process.env.EMAIL_SERVER_PASSWORD&lt;/span&gt;,
        },
      },
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;NextAuth &amp;lt;noreply@example.com&amp;gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;,
    }),
  ]
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;code&gt;EmailProvider&lt;/code&gt; to work, you also need to install the &lt;code&gt;nodemailer&lt;/code&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;$ yarn add nodemailer
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember that you also need to provide an &lt;a href=&#34;https://next-auth.js.org/adapters/overview&#34;&gt;Adapter&lt;/a&gt; to NextAuth.js so that it can persist data. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dsaltares/saltares-blog-examples/blob/main/nextauth-mailhog/pages/api/auth/%5B...nextauth%5D.js#L9&#34;&gt;my example&lt;/a&gt;, I use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://next-auth.js.org/adapters/prisma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;PrismaAdapter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-set-up-your-local-smtp-server&#34;&gt;📬 Set up your local SMTP server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mailhog/MailHog&#34;&gt;MailHog&lt;/a&gt;, an open source email testing tool that comes with an SMTP server you can run locally. Conveniently, they have a zero config Docker image!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a &lt;code&gt;docker-compose.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file or update your existing one and define the MailHog service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Docker Compose to run your database locally is a pretty good idea! In my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dsaltares/saltares-blog-examples/tree/main/nextauth-mailhog&#34;&gt;example repo&lt;/a&gt; I went for a containerised PostgreSQL database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;version&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;3.9&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;services&lt;/span&gt;:
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;mailhog&lt;/span&gt;:
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;mailhog/mailhog&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;logging&lt;/span&gt;:
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;driver&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;none&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# disable saving logs&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;ports&lt;/span&gt;:
      - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1025&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1025&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# smtp server&lt;/span&gt;
      - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;8025&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;8025&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# web ui&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add a couple of convenience scripts to your &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34; data-lang=&#34;json&#34;&gt;{
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;scripts&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;: {
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;docker:up&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;docker compose up -d&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;docker:down&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;docker compose down&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit your local &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file to configure the NextAuth.js &lt;code&gt;EmailProvider&lt;/code&gt;. Leave everything as below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;EMAIL_SERVER_HOST=localhost
EMAIL_SERVER_PORT=1025
EMAIL_SERVER_USER=email-user
EMAIL_SERVER_PASSWORD=email-pass
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-local-workflow&#34;&gt;💻 Local workflow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring up your containers and start the local development server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;$ yarn docker:up &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; yarn dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;https://localhost:3000&lt;/code&gt;, click Sign in and enter your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./img/nextjs/nextauth-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;NextAuth.js login screen&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can open &lt;code&gt;http://localhost:8025/&lt;/code&gt; and see the email with the magic link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./img/nextjs/mailhog.png&#34; alt=&#34;MailHog inbox&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🎉 That&amp;rsquo;s it, you can now manage authentication in your app and work locally without an internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Findr</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/apps-tools/teamfindr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/apps-tools/teamfindr/</guid>
      <description>⚽ Team Findr is a mobile-first app to help you find nearby pick up games, organise games with your friends and find extra players. It is completely free and has no ads.
🦠 I made it a side project during the winter holiday of 2020 as I had to self-isolate after direct contact with a covid-19 positive person. Later, my friend Cristi, did an entire UX pass and UI redesign.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;⚽ &lt;a href=&#34;https://teamfindr.saltares.com&#34;&gt;Team Findr&lt;/a&gt; is a mobile-first app to help you find nearby pick up games, organise games with your friends and find extra players. It is completely free and has no ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./img/teamfindr/teamfindr_00001.png&#34; alt=&#34;team findr screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🦠 I made it a side project during the winter holiday of 2020 as I had to self-isolate after direct contact with a covid-19 positive person. Later, my friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/cristian-iordan-26b1abb7/&#34;&gt;Cristi&lt;/a&gt;, did an entire UX pass and UI redesign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-screenshots&#34;&gt;📸 Screenshots&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;./css/hugo-easy-gallery.css&#34; /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;gallery caption-position-bottom caption-effect-slide hover-effect-zoom hover-transition&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageGallery&#34;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&#34;box&#34;&gt;
				  &lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
				    &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34; style=&#34;background-image: url(&#39;https://saltares.com/img/teamfindr/gallery//teamfindr_00002.png&#39;);&#34; &gt;
				      &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/teamfindr/gallery//teamfindr_00002.png&#34; alt=&#34;Teamfindr 00002&#34; /&gt;
				    &lt;/div&gt;
			      &lt;figcaption&gt;
		          &lt;p&gt;Teamfindr 00002&lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;/figcaption&gt;
				    &lt;a href=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/teamfindr/gallery//teamfindr_00002.png&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				  &lt;/figure&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&#34;box&#34;&gt;
				  &lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
				    &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34; style=&#34;background-image: url(&#39;https://saltares.com/img/teamfindr/gallery//teamfindr_00003.png&#39;);&#34; &gt;
				      &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/teamfindr/gallery//teamfindr_00003.png&#34; alt=&#34;Teamfindr 00003&#34; /&gt;
				    &lt;/div&gt;
			      &lt;figcaption&gt;
		          &lt;p&gt;Teamfindr 00003&lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;/figcaption&gt;
				    &lt;a href=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/teamfindr/gallery//teamfindr_00003.png&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				  &lt;/figure&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&#34;box&#34;&gt;
				  &lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
				    &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34; style=&#34;background-image: url(&#39;https://saltares.com/img/teamfindr/gallery//teamfindr_00004.png&#39;);&#34; &gt;
				      &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/teamfindr/gallery//teamfindr_00004.png&#34; alt=&#34;Teamfindr 00004&#34; /&gt;
				    &lt;/div&gt;
			      &lt;figcaption&gt;
		          &lt;p&gt;Teamfindr 00004&lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;/figcaption&gt;
				    &lt;a href=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/teamfindr/gallery//teamfindr_00004.png&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				  &lt;/figure&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;





  





&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/photoswipe.min.css&#34; integrity=&#34;sha256-sCl5PUOGMLfFYctzDW3MtRib0ctyUvI9Qsmq2wXOeBY=&#34; crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34; /&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/default-skin/default-skin.min.css&#34; integrity=&#34;sha256-BFeI1V+Vh1Rk37wswuOYn5lsTcaU96hGaI7OUVCLjPc=&#34; crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34; /&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;pswp&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; role=&#34;dialog&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;pswp__bg&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;pswp__scroll-wrap&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__container&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__item&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__item&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__item&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__ui pswp__ui--hidden&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__top-bar&#34;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__counter&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--close&#34; title=&#34;Close (Esc)&#34;&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--share&#34; title=&#34;Share&#34;&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--fs&#34; title=&#34;Toggle fullscreen&#34;&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--zoom&#34; title=&#34;Zoom in/out&#34;&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
      
      
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__preloader&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__preloader__icn&#34;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__preloader__cut&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__preloader__donut&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__share-modal pswp__share-modal--hidden pswp__single-tap&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__share-tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--arrow--left&#34; title=&#34;Previous (arrow left)&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--arrow--right&#34; title=&#34;Next (arrow right)&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__caption&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__caption__center&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-technical-details&#34;&gt;💻 Technical details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dsaltares/teamfindr&#34;&gt;Team Findr is open source&lt;/a&gt; under the MIT license. Contributions are welcome! The application is entirely written in Typescript and it has two main components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;web-app&lt;/code&gt;: client side React application. It uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Service_Worker_API&#34;&gt;Service Workers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://react-query.tanstack.com/&#34;&gt;React Query&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mui.com/getting-started/usage/&#34;&gt;MaterialUI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://leafletjs.com/&#34;&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://formik.org/&#34;&gt;Formik&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;api&lt;/code&gt;: REST API, deployed to an EC2 machine. It uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://expressjs.com/&#34;&gt;express&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mongodb.com/&#34;&gt;mongodb&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.passportjs.org/&#34;&gt;Passport&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to test and debug your localhost web app on a real Android device</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/how-to-test-and-debug-your-localhost-web-app-on-a-real-android-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/how-to-test-and-debug-your-localhost-web-app-on-a-real-android-device/</guid>
      <description>When building cross-platform web application, you can mostly get away with working locally on your desktop browser. However, from time to time you may have to deal with a pesky bug that only happens on mobile.
The desktop browser device toolbar may not be enough to reproduce it. You may actually have to use a real device! However, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to publish your app to a public URL every time you want to test whether a given change fixes the problem.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;When building cross-platform web application, you can mostly get away with working locally on your desktop browser. However, from time to time you may have to deal with a pesky bug that only happens on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desktop browser device toolbar may not be enough to reproduce it. You may actually have to use a real device! However, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to publish your app to a public URL every time you want to test whether a given change fixes the problem. That would be a massive pain in the butt!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately there is a simple trick you can use to be able to quickly iterate and test on a real mobile device while keeping an awesome developer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🏎️ Hot reload with instant feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🖥️ Access to the console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐛 Full debugger with breakpoints, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-enable-usb-debugging&#34;&gt;📱 Enable USB debugging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, make sure USB debugging is enabled on your device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;Settings -&amp;gt; About phone&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap the build number seven times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable USB debugging by going to &lt;code&gt;Settings -&amp;gt; Developer options -&amp;gt; USB Debugging&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, now you can connect your device to your development machine via USB. You should see a notification that USB debugging is enabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-tunnel-localhost&#34;&gt;🚇 Tunnel localhost&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run your local development server. I am working on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://nextjs.org/&#34;&gt;Next.js&lt;/a&gt; app, so I can just run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;$ yarn dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your web app is probably now running on &lt;code&gt;localhost&lt;/code&gt;, but your real device cannot connect directly. In order to access your local development server from a different device we can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://localtunnel.me/&#34;&gt;localtunnel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No need to install, you can use &lt;code&gt;npx&lt;/code&gt; to run it directly. Make sure to tell it to tunnel to the port your local development server is using. In my case, that is &lt;code&gt;3000&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;$ npx localtunnel --port &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;3000&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;localtunnel&lt;/code&gt; will give you a temporary URL that is accessible from anywhere in the world. In my case, I got &lt;code&gt;https://little-fox-32.loca.lt&lt;/code&gt;. You can now open that URL in the device you want to test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be mindful that, running localtunnel will essentially expose your local app traffic to their public servers. Depending on what you are working on, that may be a show stopper. In any case, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/localtunnel/localtunnel&#34;&gt;localtunnel&lt;/a&gt; is an open source tool, you could get a private server going if privacy is a concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-remote-chrome-inspector&#34;&gt;🛰️ Remote Chrome inspector&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open your Chromium based browser and enter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;chrome://inspect/#devices
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should see a list of remote targets and the pages that are open in each target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./img/remote-mobile-debugging/chrome-inspect.png&#34; alt=&#34;chrome inspect&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking &lt;code&gt;inspect&lt;/code&gt; on the one you want to debug will open the Chrome Developer Tools and connect to the remote browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./img/remote-mobile-debugging/chrome-remote-debugging.png&#34; alt=&#34;chrome remote debugging&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now see the viewport, tap around and use tools like the console, debugger, etc. You can give the URL to a colleague and have them remotely help out too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps your workflow!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 tips to make remote meetings more inclusive</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/6-tips-to-make-remote-meetings-more-inclusive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/6-tips-to-make-remote-meetings-more-inclusive/</guid>
      <description>So much goes into fostering an inclusive remote culture. It must be done deliberately, like tending to a greenhouse.
As an Engineering leader, I am committed to creating a safe environment in my team where everyone feels included.
One aspect of remote work, where lack of inclusion can really alienate your team, is meetings. So here are 6 tips on how to make them a bit more inclusive.
1. ✍️ Default to async Async communication acts as a leveller.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./img/remote-work.webp&#34; alt=&#34;remote work&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much goes into fostering an inclusive remote culture. It must be done deliberately, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.runekvist.com/remote-first&#34;&gt;tending to a greenhouse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an Engineering leader, I am committed to creating a safe environment in my team where everyone feels included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One aspect of remote work, where lack of inclusion can really alienate your team, is meetings. So here are 6 tips on how to make them a bit more inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1--default-to-async&#34;&gt;1. ✍️ Default to async&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Async communication acts as a leveller. It&amp;rsquo;s no longer about who talks first or loudest. When someone lays out a great proposal in writing, seniority starts to matter less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you really need a meeting? Consider an async discussion on a Google doc, Notion page or Github RFC issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/aulaeducation/How-we-work-together-2501716c17a64fae849b74e800b3f83d#1afa3cd0dafc4f3e986350c3e1e5837a&#34;&gt;Aula&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/company/culture/all-remote/asynchronous/#remind-people-that-async-is-more-inclusive&#34;&gt;Gitlab&lt;/a&gt; and many other remote-first companies already encourage this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2--respect-peoples-calendars&#34;&gt;2. 📆 Respect people&amp;rsquo;s calendars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When setting up a meeting, check the attendees&#39; calendar first and do not create the event if there is a clash, at least without asking first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Aula, we encourage everyone to be explicit and use Google Calendar as a communication tool by explicitly setting time for things like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🕰️ Working hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🥘 Lunch time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🏫 School run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🤸‍♂️ Workout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;❌ &amp;hellip; Any unavailable time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respecting people&amp;rsquo;s calendars is respecting their time and making them feel included. You&amp;rsquo;re basically saying that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter that they care for a dependent relative or live in a different timezone. They are an important part of the session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If making calendars work is hell 🔥, default to async!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3--send-agenda-well-in-advance&#34;&gt;3. 📝 Send agenda well in advance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only &lt;a href=&#34;https://themanagershandbook.com/working-as-a-team/running-meetings&#34;&gt;will your meetings be much more productive&lt;/a&gt;, they will also allow more introverted folks, like myself, to prepare and participate more. We will thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A meeting invite without an agenda can be extremely anxiety inducing. During those meetings, it&amp;rsquo;s usually the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hartman_Personality_Profile#Reds_core_motive&#34;&gt;red&lt;/a&gt; people who dominate the conversation. When that happens, you may be missing out on extremely valuable points of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4--observe-and-pick-up-on-cues&#34;&gt;4. 👀 Observe and pick up on cues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picking up on certain dynamics during a remote video call can be more challenging than in person although it is just as important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💬 Is someone dominating the conversation? Interject and give space for other voices. If it keeps happening, give them candid feedback 1-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🙋‍♀️ Did someone unmute and then muted on the video call? Maybe they wanted to participate but did not get the chance. Politely ask if they wanted to say something. Lots of video tools have a &amp;ldquo;raise hand&amp;rdquo; feature these days. Pay attention to raised hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🤐 Did someone not participate at all? You could ask if they want to add something. However, be mindful as not everyone may want to be put on the spot. The best is to check with them 1-1 whether that&amp;rsquo;s something they would appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5--rotate-moderators&#34;&gt;5. 👑 Rotate moderators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the scope of the meeting, it may be beneficial to rotate the moderator and let members of your team own the session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decisions made during these meetings will automatically get more &lt;a href=&#34;https://themanagershandbook.com/working-as-a-team/decision-making#getting-buy-in&#34;&gt;buy-in&lt;/a&gt; and your team will develop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6--lead-by-asking-the-silly-questions&#34;&gt;6. ✋ Lead by asking the &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;silly questions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to try encourage your team by saying &amp;ldquo;there are no silly questions&amp;rdquo;. Sure, this is nice but folks can still be intimidated and may dread judgement from their peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can do better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead by example and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23500254-the-power-of-vulnerability&#34;&gt;be vulnerable&lt;/a&gt; by sharing what you don&amp;rsquo;t know or are unsure about. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ideas.ted.com/how-showing-vulnerability-helps-build-a-stronger-team/&#34;&gt;Vulnerability builds trust&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-thanks&#34;&gt;🙌 Thanks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You made it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any good tips to make your remote meetings more inclusive?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule posts with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/schedule-posts-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/schedule-posts-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2020, I migrated this blog to Hugo and Github pages. I also set up a &amp;ldquo;push to publish&amp;rdquo; CD pipeline with Github pages.
Happy days.
🤔 A couple of days ago I wondered if there was a low effort way to schedule posts. That way, I could easily bulk some writing together and publish it later on without having to come back to it.
It&amp;rsquo;s actually trivial to set up!</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2020, I migrated this blog to &lt;a href=&#34;https://saltares.com/easily-deploy-your-hugo-site-to-github-pages/&#34;&gt;Hugo and Github pages&lt;/a&gt;. I also set up a &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;push to publish&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; CD pipeline with Github pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🤔 A couple of days ago I wondered if there was a low effort way to schedule posts. That way, I could easily bulk some writing together and publish it later on without having to come back to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s actually trivial to set up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply add a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/actions/reference/events-that-trigger-workflows#scheduled-events&#34;&gt;schedule trigger&lt;/a&gt; to your Github Action like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;Build and deploy&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;on&lt;/span&gt;:
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;push&lt;/span&gt;:
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;branches&lt;/span&gt;:
    - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;master&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;schedule&lt;/span&gt;:
    - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;cron&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;0 0 * * *&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# Once per day at midnight&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;jobs&lt;/span&gt;:
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;:
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;runs-on&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;ubuntu-latest&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;steps&lt;/span&gt;:
    - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;Checkout&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;uses&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;actions/checkout@v1&lt;/span&gt;
    - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;Setup Hugo&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;uses&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;peaceiris/actions-hugo@v2&lt;/span&gt;
    - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;Build&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;run&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/span&gt;
    - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;Deploy&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;uses&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;peaceiris/actions-gh-pages@v2&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;env&lt;/span&gt;:
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;EXTERNAL_REPOSITORY&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;dsaltares/dsaltares.github.io&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;ACTIONS_DEPLOY_KEY&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;${{ secrets.ACTIONS_DEPLOY_KEY }}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;PUBLISH_BRANCH&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;master&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;PUBLISH_DIR&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;./public&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now you can push posts that will be published into the future by setting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/front-matter/&#34;&gt;front matter&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;date&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;date: 3059-05-01T00:00:00+00:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That could be a post for future generations 😅.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; runs, it does not generate HTML for posts with dates in the future. However, our Github Action runs every day at midnight. This means that the run for May 1st 3059 will actually generate the HTML for our scheduled post and publish it 🙌.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📆 This post itself was scheduled!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to hire 8 engineers in 8 weeks</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/how-to-hire-8-engineers-in-8-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/how-to-hire-8-engineers-in-8-weeks/</guid>
      <description>Hiring engineers is top of mind for any engineering leader, this year at Aula it is the same for me. As VP Engineering I have the daunting task of tripling the size of our Engineering team. Happy to say we are well on track, in the last 8 weeks we have successfully hired 8 wonderful engineers and more than doubled our size!
I wrote this post for other engineering leaders who’ve just been given the opportunity to rapidly grow their organisations.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Hiring engineers is top of mind for any engineering leader, this year at Aula it is the same for me. As VP Engineering I have the daunting task of tripling the size of our Engineering team. Happy to say we are well on track, in the last 8 weeks we have successfully hired 8 wonderful engineers and more than doubled our size!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote this post for other engineering leaders who’ve just been given the opportunity to rapidly grow their organisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does one even start?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-context&#34;&gt;💜 Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aula.education/&#34;&gt;Aula&lt;/a&gt;, we’re building the Learning Experience Platform for higher education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aula took the decision to grow its Engineering and Product organisation at the beginning of 2021. We’re building the features that will make educators fall in love with our platform and enable them to create engaging learning experiences for their students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.aula.education/tabs/9-vision&#34;&gt;platform vision&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about what we are building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only do we want to grow fast but we want to ensure that we are focusing on building a high performing, diverse and inclusive team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thought as many engineering leaders are facing the same challenges we should share what we have learned along the way to help you do it too. And of course, if you want to come and join us in this adventure, &lt;a href=&#34;https://aulaeducation.recruitee.com/&#34;&gt;we are still hiring&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-prioritise-hiring&#34;&gt;🔝 Prioritise hiring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving my team the capacity to achieve our goals was the best way I could help, so I made hiring my number 1 priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not having a huge Recruitment team meant I had to get stuck into the process of recruitment myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at your calendar, if at least 50% of your time is not spent on hiring related activities, hiring is not your top priority and you need to fix it. Prioritising hiring will mean saying no to other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation here is to roll up your sleeves and jump into your &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Applicant_tracking_system&#34;&gt;ATS&lt;/a&gt;. Being hands on in recruitment will help you understand the candidates attracted to your organisation, refine the recruiting process and ensure that everything is kept moving forward. I spend 30 minutes every morning checking CV’s, looking at interview feedback and ensuring that I know exactly what is happening in my recruitment pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/aulaeducation/Mission-and-Virtues-at-Aula-9f2c356b2d8e44f9bfdb772ec3ca396c&#34;&gt;Uncomfortably focused&lt;/a&gt; is one of our virtues here at Aula. I know that the team has suffered in the short term because I haven’t been able to spend as much time as I would have liked supporting them. However in the long run, bringing in new team members to support what we are building has led to everyone being happier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-get-ready-to-talk-to-a-lot-of-people&#34;&gt;💬 Get ready to talk to a lot of people&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recruiting is a people game, doing this successfully means you&amp;rsquo;re about to meet a lot of new people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things is to make the time to do that. If you want your business to start growing, then this is the first thing you should do is make sure you are ok with the idea that hiring starts with conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first quarter of 2021, we had more than 1100 people enter the top of our recruiting funnel and spoke with more than 200 engineers who could potentially fit the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I send messages on LinkedIn, emails to potential candidates and ask friends in my network for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be tremendously draining for an introvert such as myself. Well, it may be draining for just about anyone! Make sure to take breaks and rest well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-standardise-the-process&#34;&gt;♻️ Standardise the process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standardising your hiring process is one of the most high leverage things you can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create wiki pages where you list the questions and problems for each stage of the process. Detail what the team wants to learn from the candidate with each question and what a poor/ok/great answer could look like. Create scorecards for each stage every interviewer will fill in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask every candidate the exact same questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will benefit you in at least three ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚖️ Consistency allows you to get better insights, compare and evaluate candidates much more easily.
📚 A documented process will help team members with little interviewer experience get trained.
🤔 Standardised interviews will reduce the biases of the process. To minimise bias, you should also have two interviewers at each stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-build-great-relationships-with-your-recruiters&#34;&gt;🤝 Build great relationships with your recruiters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no way you will double the size of your team alone. Having a top notch recruitment team is essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your whole team understands the profile you’re looking for and why they would join your company. The recruiters you are working with are an extension of your voice in the market and will be pitching candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do engineering hiring standups 3 times a week, run retrospectives every month, constantly give each other feedback and document everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-build-great-content&#34;&gt;✍️ Build great content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for your jobs to stand out, you need to tell a story. From the job ad to all your interactions with candidates through the process. You will have to raise awareness about what you’re all about and tell this story a thousand times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way is to write it or film it and put it out there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Aula, we have built great pieces of content that continue to help us through this journey:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🧠 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/aulaeducation/The-Aula-Brain-4da091a8797840108311d99815b3b36f&#34;&gt;The Aula Brain&lt;/a&gt; - our public handbook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👩‍💻 &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/aulaeducation/aula-behind-the-scenes-of-the-learning-experience-platform-our-stack-1gno&#34;&gt;A blog post about our tech stack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🛣️ &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.aula.education/&#34;&gt;Our public roadmap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💼 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/aulaeducation/How-we-work-b1af4d53998949e5b05697158261c27a&#34;&gt;How our Product Development team works together&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📽️ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zIXtXYkqqJg&amp;amp;feature=emb_logo&#34;&gt;Camila’s story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language matters. Make sure you avoid gender bias from your content as much as possible. I recommend you run your content through an analyser such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://gender-decoder.katmatfield.com/&#34;&gt;Gender Decoder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-automate-as-much-as-possible&#34;&gt;⚙️ Automate as much as possible&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be an enormous amount of repetitive work. It’s best to automate as much of it up front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of our interview scheduling is done through &lt;a href=&#34;https://calendly.com/&#34;&gt;Calendly&lt;/a&gt;. So much email back and forth has been avoided by this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time a candidate is moved through the pipeline, our ATS automatically sends emails and assigns tasks for the next steps. This saves time but also lifts a huge mental burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t remove the human element from the process, especially when it comes to giving feedback. Candidates invest valuable time interviewing with you. Anyone who is rejected deserves a customised message with specific feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-pre-book-interview-slots&#34;&gt;📆 Pre-book interview slots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The engineers in your team will have to do a ton of interviews. This takes a lot of time and focus from sprint work. It’s not just the interview slot but the prior prep and evaluation that comes after as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Context switching can kill productivity and increase stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help engineers focus, have pre-booked weekly interview slots. Predictability will facilitate better time management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-track-everything--iterate&#34;&gt;🔍 Track everything &amp;amp; iterate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the data to make better decisions and set targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track everything. Measure your data and analyse it to make better decisions that can help you optimise to achieve your goals. Data can help you make changes to attract more applicants, avoid losing candidates or screen better and save engineering interviewer time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-thats-it&#34;&gt;🙌 That’s it!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really keen to hear if you think I missed anything important and let me know if you found this useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s so much more that could be covered!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🏫 Interviewer training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👩‍🎓 Onboarding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🚀 And more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronolooper</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/game-jams/chronolooper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/game-jams/chronolooper/</guid>
      <description>.Get &#34;linkText&#34;    They put you in a facility and ran all sorts of experiments because you can control time. Now you are stuck in a time loop!
🎮 The game Plague is an infinite action platformer with procedurally generated levels. It&amp;rsquo;s got gamepad support and you can play it from your browser.
💻 Ludum Dare 47 Chronolooper was developed using Godot Engine for Ludum Dare 47, a 72h jam.</description>
      <content>&lt;div
  style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 24%; height: 0; margin-bottom: 1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe
     src=&#34;https://itch.io/embed/773332&#34; 
    frameborder=&#34;0&#34;
    webkitallowfullscreen
    mozallowfullscreen
    allowfullscreen
    style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34;
  &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://david-saltares.itch.io/chronolooper&#34;&gt;
        .Get &#34;linkText&#34;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They put you in a facility and ran all sorts of experiments because you can control time. Now you are stuck in a time loop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-the-game&#34;&gt;🎮 The game&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plague is an infinite action platformer with procedurally generated levels. It&amp;rsquo;s got gamepad support and you can play it from your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-ludum-dare-47&#34;&gt;💻 Ludum Dare 47&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronolooper was developed using &lt;a href=&#34;https://godotengine.org/&#34;&gt;Godot Engine&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/47&#34;&gt;Ludum Dare 47&lt;/a&gt;, a 72h jam. The theme was &lt;em&gt;Stuck in a loop&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-more-info&#34;&gt;💡 More info&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Game Jam: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/47&#34;&gt;Ludum Dare 47&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development time: 72h&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technology: Godoot Engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/senthe&#34;&gt;@senthe&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/d_saltares&#34;&gt;@d_saltares&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dsaltares/ludumdare-47&#34;&gt;Source code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-screenshots&#34;&gt;📷 Screenshots&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;./css/hugo-easy-gallery.css&#34; /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;gallery caption-position-bottom caption-effect-slide hover-effect-zoom hover-transition&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageGallery&#34;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&#34;box&#34;&gt;
				  &lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
				    &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34; style=&#34;background-image: url(&#39;https://saltares.com/img/chronolooper/gallery/chronolooper-1.png&#39;);&#34; &gt;
				      &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/chronolooper/gallery/chronolooper-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chronolooper 1&#34; /&gt;
				    &lt;/div&gt;
			      &lt;figcaption&gt;
		          &lt;p&gt;Chronolooper 1&lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;/figcaption&gt;
				    &lt;a href=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/chronolooper/gallery/chronolooper-1.png&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				  &lt;/figure&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&#34;box&#34;&gt;
				  &lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
				    &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34; style=&#34;background-image: url(&#39;https://saltares.com/img/chronolooper/gallery/chronolooper-2.png&#39;);&#34; &gt;
				      &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/chronolooper/gallery/chronolooper-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chronolooper 2&#34; /&gt;
				    &lt;/div&gt;
			      &lt;figcaption&gt;
		          &lt;p&gt;Chronolooper 2&lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;/figcaption&gt;
				    &lt;a href=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/chronolooper/gallery/chronolooper-2.png&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				  &lt;/figure&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&#34;box&#34;&gt;
				  &lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
				    &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34; style=&#34;background-image: url(&#39;https://saltares.com/img/chronolooper/gallery/chronolooper-3.png&#39;);&#34; &gt;
				      &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/chronolooper/gallery/chronolooper-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chronolooper 3&#34; /&gt;
				    &lt;/div&gt;
			      &lt;figcaption&gt;
		          &lt;p&gt;Chronolooper 3&lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;/figcaption&gt;
				    &lt;a href=&#34;https://saltares.com/img/chronolooper/gallery/chronolooper-3.png&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				  &lt;/figure&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;





  





&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/photoswipe.min.css&#34; integrity=&#34;sha256-sCl5PUOGMLfFYctzDW3MtRib0ctyUvI9Qsmq2wXOeBY=&#34; crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34; /&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/default-skin/default-skin.min.css&#34; integrity=&#34;sha256-BFeI1V+Vh1Rk37wswuOYn5lsTcaU96hGaI7OUVCLjPc=&#34; crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34; /&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;pswp&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; role=&#34;dialog&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;pswp__bg&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;pswp__scroll-wrap&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__container&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__item&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__item&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__item&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__ui pswp__ui--hidden&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__top-bar&#34;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__counter&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--close&#34; title=&#34;Close (Esc)&#34;&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--share&#34; title=&#34;Share&#34;&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--fs&#34; title=&#34;Toggle fullscreen&#34;&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--zoom&#34; title=&#34;Zoom in/out&#34;&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
      
      
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__preloader&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__preloader__icn&#34;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__preloader__cut&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__preloader__donut&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__share-modal pswp__share-modal--hidden pswp__single-tap&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__share-tooltip&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--arrow--left&#34; title=&#34;Previous (arrow left)&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;button class=&#34;pswp__button pswp__button--arrow--right&#34; title=&#34;Next (arrow right)&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__caption&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;pswp__caption__center&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
