<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on David Saltares</title>
    <link>https://saltares.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on David Saltares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saltares.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I got into Engineering management</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/how-i-got-into-engineering-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/how-i-got-into-engineering-management/</guid>
      <description>Recently, people, who are considering becoming Engineering Managers, have asked about my own experience.
How did I get into it? How did I know it was what I wanted to do?
The answer may be interesting to others, so I wrote it down.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to note that becoming a manager is not a promotion. It&amp;rsquo;s a career change. There&amp;rsquo;s a myriad of reasons not to be a manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 books you should read as a new Engineering Manager</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/5-books-you-should-read-as-a-new-engineering-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/5-books-you-should-read-as-a-new-engineering-manager/</guid>
      <description>Stepping into the engineering manager role is challenging. The skills that got you there are not the skills that will make you succeed in your new role. If that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, you will feel lonely. The folks who were your peers are now your reports. Those relationships are entirely different now.
You will need plenty of support.
Having a mentor was certainly invaluable, and you should aim to have one. A few selected books gave me tremendously helpful insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The David Test - An updated Joel Test for 2022</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/the-david-test-an-updated-joel-test-for-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/the-david-test-an-updated-joel-test-for-2022/</guid>
      <description>The famous Joel Test is a super quick and fun way to evaluate an engineering organisation by answering 12 simple &amp;ldquo;yes or no&amp;rdquo; questions. At the end, you get a score over 12. There is a problem however.
The test is now 22 years old 😱.
Tools and processes to build software have changed a fair bit over the last two decades. What was considered a potential nice to have, may have become an absolute basic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote work panel at UOC (Spanish)</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/remote-work-panel-at-uoc-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/remote-work-panel-at-uoc-spanish/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s already been a while but, back in November last year, I participated in a panel about remote work organised by the Universitat Oberta de Catalunya (UOC). It was fantastic to share thoughts and opinions with other folks that had different backgrounds and experiences.
📽️ You can watch the entire session here although it is in Spanish.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticky nav bar on scroll with React hooks</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/sticky-nav-bar-on-scroll-with-react-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/sticky-nav-bar-on-scroll-with-react-hooks/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I built a small React application that had a header, a navigation bar underneath and then the content. After scrolling past the header, the navigation bar was supposed to stay at the top and not scroll away.
Like so.
 Making the navigation bar position: fixed; top 0; was not going to cut it because the header had to come first unless we scrolled past the navigation bar.
I wanted to keep the component that controls the layout as simple as possible, so I abstracted the stickiness logic into a useSticky hook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve your NextAuth.js app local development experience with a dockerized SMTP server</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/improve-your-nextauth.js-app-local-development-experience-with-a-dockerized-smtp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/improve-your-nextauth.js-app-local-development-experience-with-a-dockerized-smtp-server/</guid>
      <description>NextAuth.js makes it shockingly easy to add authentication to Next.js apps. It&amp;rsquo;s free, open source, it lets you own your data and it supports a ton of identity providers, including one time passwords or &amp;ldquo;magic links&amp;rdquo;.
Working with NextAuth.js is trivial, it sounds too good to be true!
Of course, there is a catch&amp;hellip;
The developer experience worsens because you now need a network connection to log into your locally running app, even if your database is also local.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to test and debug your localhost web app on a real Android device</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/how-to-test-and-debug-your-localhost-web-app-on-a-real-android-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/how-to-test-and-debug-your-localhost-web-app-on-a-real-android-device/</guid>
      <description>When building cross-platform web application, you can mostly get away with working locally on your desktop browser. However, from time to time you may have to deal with a pesky bug that only happens on mobile.
The desktop browser device toolbar may not be enough to reproduce it. You may actually have to use a real device! However, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to publish your app to a public URL every time you want to test whether a given change fixes the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 tips to make remote meetings more inclusive</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/6-tips-to-make-remote-meetings-more-inclusive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/6-tips-to-make-remote-meetings-more-inclusive/</guid>
      <description>So much goes into fostering an inclusive remote culture. It must be done deliberately, like tending to a greenhouse.
As an Engineering leader, I am committed to creating a safe environment in my team where everyone feels included.
One aspect of remote work, where lack of inclusion can really alienate your team, is meetings. So here are 6 tips on how to make them a bit more inclusive.
1. ✍️ Default to async Async communication acts as a leveller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule posts with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/schedule-posts-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/schedule-posts-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2020, I migrated this blog to Hugo and Github pages. I also set up a &amp;ldquo;push to publish&amp;rdquo; CD pipeline with Github pages.
Happy days.
🤔 A couple of days ago I wondered if there was a low effort way to schedule posts. That way, I could easily bulk some writing together and publish it later on without having to come back to it.
It&amp;rsquo;s actually trivial to set up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to hire 8 engineers in 8 weeks</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/how-to-hire-8-engineers-in-8-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/how-to-hire-8-engineers-in-8-weeks/</guid>
      <description>Hiring engineers is top of mind for any engineering leader, this year at Aula it is the same for me. As VP Engineering I have the daunting task of tripling the size of our Engineering team. Happy to say we are well on track, in the last 8 weeks we have successfully hired 8 wonderful engineers and more than doubled our size!
I wrote this post for other engineering leaders who’ve just been given the opportunity to rapidly grow their organisations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
