<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on David Saltares</title>
    <link>https://saltares.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on David Saltares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saltares.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Improve your NextAuth.js app local development experience with a dockerized SMTP server</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/improve-your-nextauth.js-app-local-development-experience-with-a-dockerized-smtp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/improve-your-nextauth.js-app-local-development-experience-with-a-dockerized-smtp-server/</guid>
      <description>NextAuth.js makes it shockingly easy to add authentication to Next.js apps. It&amp;rsquo;s free, open source, it lets you own your data and it supports a ton of identity providers, including one time passwords or &amp;ldquo;magic links&amp;rdquo;.
Working with NextAuth.js is trivial, it sounds too good to be true!
Of course, there is a catch&amp;hellip;
The developer experience worsens because you now need a network connection to log into your locally running app, even if your database is also local.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to test and debug your localhost web app on a real Android device</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/how-to-test-and-debug-your-localhost-web-app-on-a-real-android-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/how-to-test-and-debug-your-localhost-web-app-on-a-real-android-device/</guid>
      <description>When building cross-platform web application, you can mostly get away with working locally on your desktop browser. However, from time to time you may have to deal with a pesky bug that only happens on mobile.
The desktop browser device toolbar may not be enough to reproduce it. You may actually have to use a real device! However, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to publish your app to a public URL every time you want to test whether a given change fixes the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 tips to make remote meetings more inclusive</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/6-tips-to-make-remote-meetings-more-inclusive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/6-tips-to-make-remote-meetings-more-inclusive/</guid>
      <description>So much goes into fostering an inclusive remote culture. It must be done deliberately, like tending to a greenhouse.
As an Engineering leader, I am committed to creating a safe environment in my team where everyone feels included.
One aspect of remote work, where lack of inclusion can really alienate your team, is meetings. So here are 6 tips on how to make them a bit more inclusive.
1. ✍️ Default to async Async communication acts as a leveller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule posts with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/schedule-posts-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/schedule-posts-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2020, I migrated this blog to Hugo and Github pages. I also set up a &amp;ldquo;push to publish&amp;rdquo; CD pipeline with Github pages.
Happy days.
🤔 A couple of days ago I wondered if there was a low effort way to schedule posts. That way, I could easily bulk some writing together and publish it later on without having to come back to it.
It&amp;rsquo;s actually trivial to set up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to hire 8 engineers in 8 weeks</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/how-to-hire-8-engineers-in-8-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/how-to-hire-8-engineers-in-8-weeks/</guid>
      <description>Hiring engineers is top of mind for any engineering leader, this year at Aula it is the same for me. As VP Engineering I have the daunting task of tripling the size of our Engineering team. Happy to say we are well on track, in the last 8 weeks we have successfully hired 8 wonderful engineers and more than doubled our size!
I wrote this post for other engineering leaders who’ve just been given the opportunity to rapidly grow their organisations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doodle: a crazy drawing &amp; guessing game</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/doodle-a-crazy-drawing-guessing-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/doodle-a-crazy-drawing-guessing-game/</guid>
      <description>✏️ Introducing Doodle, a crazy drawing &amp;amp; guessing chain game. Think Pictionary meets Telephone. Better played with your friends over a video call!

🏠 Doodle is a little side project I made during covid-19 confinement to play with friends while we cannot meet face to face. Initially, I thought the crisis would end before I finished it, which would make me lose interest. Little did I know! Not only did I finish it, Doodle has already lightened up the mood in a few remote evenings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plague: a Godot Wild Jam 18 game postmortem</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/plague-a-godot-wild-jam-18-game-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/plague-a-godot-wild-jam-18-game-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, Jay Cano and I took part in the week-long Godot Wild Jam 18 and submitted Plague. Here are some of my personal thoughts on how we did and maybe some lessons for the future!
📈 Results Out of 43 submissions, we ranked 6th overall. That is the top 13th percentile. More importantly, we ranked 3th for fun or top 6th percentile. For the sake of comparison, Onederful Wizard, which we submitted to the GMTK 2019, ranked 294 out of 2617 entries (top 11th percentile).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Delivery pipeline for Godot and itch.io</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/continuous-delivery-pipeline-for-godot-and-itch.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/continuous-delivery-pipeline-for-godot-and-itch.io/</guid>
      <description>During the recent Godot Wild Jam 18, I implemented a full Continuous Delivery system to automatically publish Plague, our entry, on itch.io. The pipeline relies on Github Actions, the same mechanism I use to build and deploy this very blog.
Setting up your own is easy peasy and possibly free!
⚒️ Pipeline overview  Someone pushes to the master branch on the remote repo. The game is exported for all available platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plague - Godot Wild Jam 18</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/plague-godot-wild-jam-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 14:35:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/plague-godot-wild-jam-18/</guid>
      <description>My friend Jay and I recently took part in Godot Wild Jam, a week long game jam where entries must be made using Godot Engine.
We had an absolute blast! The result is Plague, a procedurally generated action platformer. You can play it in the browser and use either a gamepad or keyboard!
 .Get &#34;linkText&#34;    Don&amp;rsquo;t congratulate us on the visuals just yet, we used the Rogue Noir asset pack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSDEM 2020 - Survival Guide</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/fosdem-2020-survival-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/fosdem-2020-survival-guide/</guid>
      <description>This weekend FOSDEM 2020 will take place in Brussels. FOSDEM is a yearly conference about open source software. It&amp;rsquo;s totally free and no registration is required. As a consequence, it&amp;rsquo;s massive and chaotic, but also a lot of fun! I attended in 2017 and loved it, so I really look forward to this year&amp;rsquo;s edition.
If this is your first time, here&amp;rsquo;s a few tips that may come in handy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily deploy your Hugo site to Github Pages</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/easily-deploy-your-hugo-site-to-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/easily-deploy-your-hugo-site-to-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>I had been using a DigitalOcean droplet to host this blog and personal projects for years. But&amp;hellip; Do I really need to spend the $6/month? It&amp;rsquo;s just a static Hugo site, which Github pages can do for free. Game hosting on itch.io is also free, it even gives you a mechanism to embed your web games. Looks like I&amp;rsquo;d be sorted!
Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple CD workflow for deploying a Huge site to Github pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run automated tests for your Godot game on CI</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/run-godot-tests-ci-travis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/run-godot-tests-ci-travis/</guid>
      <description>Automated testing in gamedev Nowadays, most people agree that automated testing is absolutely crucial for all software development. Not so much when it comes to games development though. I still believe that the games industry would be able to iterate and ship faster by introducing unit and integration testing in the right places.
Godot and Gut Butch Wesley appears to be onboard, considering he created Gut, an automated testing framework for the Godot Game Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load test your backend services with locust.io at Pycon ES 2017</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/general/load-test-your-services-with-locust-at-pycon-es/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 20:49:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/general/load-test-your-services-with-locust-at-pycon-es/</guid>
      <description>PyCon ES 2017 was an absolute blast!
The talks were very interesting and they&amp;rsquo;re all freely available on their Youtube channel.
Celebrating PyCon ES 2017 in Caceres, located in southern Spain, was a great choice. Beautiful medieval city center where some scenes in Game of Thrones were filmed, plus cheap and delicious food.
   Caceres 01
      Caceres 02
      Caceres 03</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Come to PyCon ES 2017!</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/general/come-to-pycon-es-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 22:03:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/general/come-to-pycon-es-2017/</guid>
      <description>PyCon ES 2017, which will be running from September 22nd to September 24th in Cáceres, Spain. I&amp;rsquo;ll be attending alongside some Bloomberg colleagues as we are one of the main sponsors of the event. If you have tickets, definitely come say hi!
I&amp;rsquo;ll be helping out at a couple of presentations:
 Bloomberg - Landing on a top Tech Tier Company Load test your backend with locust.io  For those not coming, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure all the talks will be recorded and made publicly available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JSConf EU 2017 - Recommended talks</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/general/jsconf-eu-2017-recommended-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 15:39:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/general/jsconf-eu-2017-recommended-talks/</guid>
      <description>JSConf EU is one of the biggest JS conferences in Europe and I was lucky enough to attend its 2017 edition earlier this month. This year the event took place in Arena Berlin, a place by the river, typically dedicated to concerts in the east side of the German capital.
Overall, it was a pretty awesome weekend and although I wish there were more talks on advanced technical topics, I understand the event is more focused on community and diversity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ludum Dare 38 - Theme ideas</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/ludum-dare-38-theme-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 22:07:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/ludum-dare-38-theme-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Ludum Dare 38 starts in a couple of hours. This one is special as it marks the 15th anniversary of the biggest weekend game development friendly competition in the world!
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know about Ludum Dare and are interested, check the documentary they just released.
I was thinking of participating using Godot Engine. I have a couple of social compromises this weekend and, honestly, I am a bit scared of failing miserably, so I&amp;rsquo;m not too sure how far I&amp;rsquo;ll take this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSDEM 2017</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/general/fosdem-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 12:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/general/fosdem-2017/</guid>
      <description>Two weekends ago I attended FOSDEM in Brussels for the first time and it was awesome. FOSDEM is a free conference about software development and open source with no registration required. Just show up, meet the community and learn new things.
Here are my highlights.
Planning With over 8k developers, 600 talks and 50 tracks spread across the university campus, planning is essential. Popular talks would fill up the rooms very early and the best option was to attend the previous one and get a spot in advance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Godot Engine out for the #godotjam</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/trying-godot-engine-out-for-the-godotjam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 11:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/trying-godot-engine-out-for-the-godotjam/</guid>
      <description>Godot Engine caught my eye a while back as a serious open source alternative to the ubiquitous Unity. Some of you may know I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with the Libgdx project for some time, I even wrote a book about it!
There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with Libgdx, I absolutely love the project and the more than welcoming community around it.
The problem is that shipping a game is hard. Doing so whilst working a full time job is harder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration from Wordpress to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/general/migration-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 12:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/general/migration-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>At long last, I got around to do something I had been meaning to do for a very long time. I migrated this Wordpress blog over to a statically generated site powered by Hugo.
That&amp;rsquo;s 6 years or over 300 posts worth of content.
Why not stay with Wordpress? First of all, I wanted to move away from Wordpress because it&amp;rsquo;s heavy and requires quite a bit of setup: PHP, database, plugins and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.7.3 released!</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-3-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 14:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-3-released/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a new Ashley release, check the changes for 1.7.3 below:
 API addition: Adds ‘createComponent()&amp;quot; method to Engine class. Commit 07fc2ba6bcd9996c472c651b56b57b32fd8fd3a7. API addition: Adds ‘createEntity()&amp;quot; method to Engine class. Commit 45dd7e0e4a52c8d65f520fac4e8f4e83471b215b. API addition: Adds ‘addAndReturn()&amp;quot; method to Entity class. Commit 423148a2719873efb50d4f2b3982c247df4fceca. Bug fix: Fixes systems going out of priority order after removal. Issue #237. Bug fix: Fixes returning pooled entity to the entity pool twice. Issue #221. Update: uses Travis for CI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.7.2 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/general/ashley-1-7-2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 21:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/general/ashley-1-7-2-released/</guid>
      <description>Small Ashley release, check the changes for 1.7.2 below:
 Bug fix: Engine doesn&amp;rsquo;t use EntitySystem iterator(). Bug fix: Fixes Engine left unusable, in the updating state, after an uncaught exception in a subsystem. Bug fix: Fixes FamilyManager not cleaning up properly when a triggering a listener that throws.  To use it, change your dependency to com.badlogicgames.gdx:ashley:1.7.2. The new nightly dependency is com.badlogicgames.gdx:ashley:1.7.3-SNAPSHOT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-in console for Libgdx games</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/built-in-console-for-libgdx-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 16:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/built-in-console-for-libgdx-games/</guid>
      <description>A lot of games come with a built-in console that lets you enter commands, which is especially useful during development. Most times, it gets disabled before shipping although, occasionally, devs let you bring it up and enter cheat codes. CryEngine comes with a built-in console.
When you&amp;quot;re testing a new feature you just wrote, it can be incredibly useful to pause, reset the scene, teleport your character, become invincible, switch to a different level or even adjust some parameters in the AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2D vision system with Ashley and Box2D</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/2d-vision-system-with-ashley-and-box2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 16:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/2d-vision-system-with-ashley-and-box2d/</guid>
      <description>In Sloppynauts the player had to remain undetected, avoiding CCTV cameras and alien baddies. We constantly had to determine who could see who and whether the player was hidden behind something. We wrote a nice reusable system using Ashley and Box2D and I think it&amp;quot;d be a shame if it went to waste. So here it is in case you&amp;quot;d like to use it.
This 2D vision system is generic enough to work with both side-scrolling and top-down games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sloppynauts, our LibGDXJAM entry</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/sloppynauts-our-libgdxjam-entry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 23:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/sloppynauts-our-libgdxjam-entry/</guid>
      <description>After a crazy weekend before the deadline, we finally managed to put something playable together for LibGDXJAM.
We&amp;quot;d love you to have a go, and leave some feedback.
 We are definitely aware of the shortcomings of the game. We spent a lot of the jam working on a custom Overlap2D level loader and not so much on actual content, so you can actually finish the game in under a minute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.7.1 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 12:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-1-released/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a new Ashley release, check the changes for 1.7.1 below:
 API addition: expose IntervalSystem interval value (read-only). Bug fix: fixed pending entity operations not being processed in the right order. Bug fix: fixed adding component in empty family EntityListener causing wrong EntityListener calls. Bug fix: fixed some entity operations not being performed under special circumstances. Internals: split Engine internals into loosely coupled, single responsibility smaller classes. Update: uses Libgdx 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibGDXJAM update #3</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdxjam-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 11:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdxjam-update-3/</guid>
      <description>Oh my God, enter panic mode, just 8 days left until the #LibGDXJAM deadline! We&amp;rsquo;ve been hard at work, especially @DrillerDev who&amp;rsquo;s pushed the character design and animation.
Look at this bad boy for instance, better not to mess with his alien gun.
Or the beholder powered alien surveillance.
Please, ignore the placeholder environment art, it&amp;rsquo;s the textures from the Overlap2D example project. Our chubby astronaut can run, crouch, jump and push boxes around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibGDXJAM New Year&#39;s update</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdxjam-new-years-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 19:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdxjam-new-years-update/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;quot;re halfway through the #libGDXJAM and some work has been done between Christmas and New Year&amp;rsquo;s eve.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a few updates.
 @DrillerDev as joined us as an artist and has already produced some awesome concepts. Alberto and I have been working on an Overlap2D scene loader and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much working supporting a bunch of things: composites, textures, lights, physics and particles. We have a somewhat buggy physics based platformer movement system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibJDX jam is on: Life in Space</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libjdxjam-is-on-life-in-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 12:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libjdxjam-is-on-life-in-space/</guid>
      <description>Check the keynote and all the awkward moments from the dev team, including mine!
The theme is Life in Space and I&amp;quot;m teaming up with Alberto for #libGDXJAM and here&amp;rsquo;s our idea:
 Abe&amp;rsquo;s Oddysee meets This War of Mine meets Boogerman&amp;hellip; in space!
 A bunch of dangerously unprepared astronauts land on a strange planet only to find out it&amp;rsquo;s inhabited by big fat angry aliens with guns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx Cookbook is now as cheap as beer!</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/general/libgdx-cookbook-is-now-as-cheap-as-beer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 10:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/general/libgdx-cookbook-is-now-as-cheap-as-beer/</guid>
      <description>This holiday season you can buy Libgdx Cross-platform Game Development Cookbook just for what a beer would set you back! It&amp;rsquo;s either £4, $6 or 5€ until January 6th. So, do you liver a favour, don&amp;rsquo;t down that extra pint and learn Libgdx! Remember we keep our samples up to date with the latest Libgdx releases on GitHub.
Happy holidays!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on unit testing for Ashley and games in general</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/thoughts-on-unit-testing-for-ashley-and-games-in-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 15:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/thoughts-on-unit-testing-for-ashley-and-games-in-general/</guid>
      <description>Shortly after we moved Ashley into the Libgdx family, we started writing unit tests for every single component in the framework using jUnit.
Unit testing goodness That was over a year and a half ago and it has proven to be a huge win for many reasons.
 Issue reporters can (and should) include a test that breaks as a way of explaining the problem. We can then easily include it into the suite, fix it and prevent future regressions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.7.0 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 21:48:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-0-released/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a new Ashley release, check the changes for 1.7.0 below:
 API change: removed UUIDs from entities, users should implement their own ID system when needed. This helps with networked games. Update: components are added/removed immediately, listeners are notified after the current system finishes updating. Bug fix: fixed entity listeners not being called if a component is added inside another listener. Bug fix: does not allocate memory inside updateFamilyMembership(). Update: uses Libgdx 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Win a free digital copy of Libgdx Cookbook</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/win-a-free-digital-copy-of-libgdx-cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 12:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/win-a-free-digital-copy-of-libgdx-cookbook/</guid>
      <description>Update: the list of winners is available as a public draw. Congratulations and thanks for the support! The Libgdx Cookbook discount will continue until September the 30th. If you help us spread the word by retweeting the following message, you&amp;quot;ll have a chance of getting one of the three free digital copies of the book we&amp;quot;ll be giving away.
Libgdx Cookbook is 50% off, use the code: &amp;quot;LCPGDC50&amp;quot; and RT to enter a raffle for 3 digital copies of the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx Cookbook 50 off!</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-50-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 12:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-50-off/</guid>
      <description>Libgdx Cross-platform Game Development Cookbook is 50% off until September 30th if you get it from Packt&amp;rsquo;s website using the code LCPGDC50. You have to admit it&amp;rsquo;s a total steal, considering it&amp;rsquo;s the most complete and up to date Libgdx book out there.
 Over 75 to-the-point articles that will show you how to leverage a particular aspect of Libgdx for your game. Every article is accompanied by a runnable sample available on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new side project: Conjugate is now online</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/conjugate-is-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 11:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/conjugate-is-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Conjugate is a free, multi-language verb conjugator service and it is now available at saltares.com/conjugate.
It&amp;quot;dead easy: select the target language, enter the infinitive form, either in English or the target language, and press the Conjugate button to get a nice list with all its conjugated forms. You don&amp;rsquo;t know how to conjugate a verb whilst on the go? No worries, Conjugate&amp;rsquo;s design is responsive, which means it looks neat on any device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.6.0 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-6-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 22:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-6-0-released/</guid>
      <description>A new Ashley package has shipped, making 1.6.0 the latest stable version. Here&amp;rsquo;s the summary of the changes:
 API change: Component is now an interface. API addition: adds getEngine() to EntitySystem. API addition: EntityListeners now are notified by priority order. API consistency: defines what happens when an Entity is added twice to an Engine and when we try do nested updates. We throw an exception in both cases. API consistency: adding an EntitySystem of the same class twice replaces the previous one, just like it has always happened when adding Components to an Entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx at Intel Buzz Workshop Stockholm 2015: pictures and video</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-intel-buzz-workshop-stockholm-2015-pictures-and-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 21:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-intel-buzz-workshop-stockholm-2015-pictures-and-video/</guid>
      <description>As I recently mentioned, a couple of weeks ago I flew to Stockholm to attend the Intel Buzz Workshop, a conference focused on mobile games development where I preached the perks of Libgdx. The event had a great turnout and my talk seemed to have been well received. Moreover, I also got to meet cool people IRL such as Adrian, the guy behind the Artemis ECS.
For those who missed it and would like to watch me ramble about how brilliant Libgdx is for a whole 20 minutes, here is the video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx at Intel Buzz Workshop Stockholm 2015</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-intel-buzz-workshop-stockholm-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 21:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-intel-buzz-workshop-stockholm-2015/</guid>
      <description>Quick update to let you know I have been invited to talk about all Libgdx things at Intel Buzz Workshop 2015, which will take place in Stockholm on July 17th. It will be a one day conference on mobile games development and will feature talks on virtual reality, Unreal Engine 4 and lots of cool stuff, check the programme for more details.
Register if you are interested, tickets are free until July 6th!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx Cookbook samples updated to support Libgdx 1.6.0</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-samples-updated-to-support-libgdx-1-6-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 11:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-samples-updated-to-support-libgdx-1-6-0/</guid>
      <description>Haven&amp;rsquo;t bought Libgdx Cross-platform Game Development Cookbook yet? Stop reading and go get it!
Quick update to inform you that I just updated the samples repository to use Libgdx 1.6.0 and Ashley 1.5.0, both recently released.
Libgdx 1.6.0 introduces changes in our font rendering API, which require a few minor tweaks to the framework calls, nothing major.
7 months after the release of the book, we continue to support it. Rest assured, it is the most up to date Libgdx publication at this point in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.5.0 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-5-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 10:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-5-0-released/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the contributors, here&amp;rsquo;s a new version of Ashley, which now stands at 1.5.0. A new version of your favorite component based entity framework is out.
The version comes with a bunch of bug fixes that, hopefully, will iron out some of the rough edges in Ashley.
 API addition: adds getFamily() method to IntervalIteratingSystem and IteratingSystem. API change: IntervalSystem‘s update() method is now final, as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to override it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conjugate</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/conjugate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 17:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/conjugate/</guid>
      <description>For the past few weeks working on a new toy: Conjugate. It&amp;rsquo;s probably easier if I just stick a summary of the GitHub readme here.
Conjugate is a verb conjugator service. Enter a verb in English and get the conjugations for all tenses in a variety of languages.
Reason to be When learning a new language, it is very common to struggle with verb conjugations. For example:
 I want to know the third person singular form (masculine) of the future perfect tense of the verb to eat in French.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New domain and hosting</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/general/new-domain-and-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 14:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/general/new-domain-and-hosting/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over 5 years since I registered siondream.com. At that time, I also signed up for a shared hosting plan with Hostgator. Unfortunately, I&amp;rsquo;m no longer 16 years old, so the domain felt a bit dated. A change was long overdue, but I can be real lazy during the weekend. Finally I got around to do a proper migration of both domain name and hosting.
Welcome to saltares.com!
Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief of my experience with Hostgator and the migration process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx Cookbook samples updated</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-samples-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 23:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-samples-updated/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months since Libgdx Cross-platform Game Development Cookbook came out. Quite a few things have happened since then in the Libgdx world, libraries are updated and some things break over time.
As promised, we have updated our samples repository to use the latest versions of Libgdx (1.5.5), Ashley (1.4.0), gdx-ai (1.5.0) and RoboVM (1.0.0) among others. Luckily enough, only a few changes were necessary to make everything work again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.4.0 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-4-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 16:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-4-0-released/</guid>
      <description>A new version of Ashley, your favourite component based entity framework is out. The 1.4.0 version comes with a bunch of bug fixes that, hopefully, will iron out some of the rough edges in Ashley.
 API deprecation: finallt removed the Family.getFor() methods. In order to retrieve a family, you can do Family.all().one().exclude().get(). API change: makes family Builder package protected. Bug fix: EntityOperation and ComponentOperation are now properly reset when put back into their pools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2D Game Art for Programmers copyright infringement</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/general/2d-game-art-for-programmers-copyright-infringement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 22:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/general/2d-game-art-for-programmers-copyright-infringement/</guid>
      <description>This story really upset me, but let&amp;rsquo;s start from the beginning for context&amp;rsquo;s sake.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been following Chris Hildenbrand&amp;rsquo;s blog 2D Game Art for Programmers since the very beginning because it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely amazing. He gives hope to talentless and desperate programmers like me, so we can go and make games that won&amp;rsquo;t make people want to pull their eyes out. Just a few intelligently placed shapes, some smart shading and you&amp;rsquo;ve got decent art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx at the LJC: slides and video</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-the-ljc-slides-video-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 21:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-the-ljc-slides-video-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I had the pleasure to deliver a talk about Libgdx at the London Java Community Meetup. To my surprise, there was a pretty decent turnout. The audience was lovely, seemed engaged and asked quite a few questions. No awkward silence at the end.
 Woohoo!
 Thanks a lot to everyone who attended, and to the organisers who made it possible. We must catch up next time at the pub afterwards!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx at the London Java Community Meetup</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/general/libgdx-at-the-london-java-community-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 13:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/general/libgdx-at-the-london-java-community-meetup/</guid>
      <description>Next Tuesday 3rd of February I will be talking about Libgdx at the London Java Community Meetup. Things won&amp;rsquo;t get too technical, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce the framework, explain why it&amp;rsquo;s so awesome, show who is currently using it in commercial products and give a quick demo at the end. Of course I won&amp;rsquo;t miss this golden opportunity to cheekily mention my Libgdx Cookbook!
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, sign up and come to the The Skills Matter eXchange, doors open at 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.3.3 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/ashley-1-3-3-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 11:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/ashley-1-3-3-released/</guid>
      <description>As you can see, Ashley development has slowed down a bit. I would like to think it&amp;rsquo;s because we have a feature rich and stable framework rather than people having lost interest! Anyhow, there&amp;rsquo;s still been quite a bit of progress, enough to warrant a new release.
Ashley 1.3.3 is now out.
 API addition: added getEntity() method to Engine, it is now possible to retrieve entities by their ID. This will ease networked entity systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recover history with Git</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/computing/recover-history-with-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/computing/recover-history-with-git/</guid>
      <description>While doing some cleanup of old feature branches, I accidentally deleted one that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been pushed to origin yet. However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise at the time.
After a couple of weeks, a hundred commits and many other branches mingling about, I found myself looking for the one I had previously deleted.
 Oh noes!
 Luckily for me, Git is somewhat idiot-proof and rarely truly deletes anything. Using git reflog you can list the tip of branches, including the deleted ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Clean Code</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/computing/book-review-clean-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 21:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/computing/book-review-clean-code/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the pleasure to attend a few lectures by Robert C. Martin, also known as Uncle Bob. He&amp;rsquo;s a software consultant, speaker and fierce advocate of agile methodologies as well as TDD. Not only were the talks entertaining, but also deeply inspirational.
Seeking more information on his ideas, I decided that it would be good to take a look at his flagship book, Clean Code.
And so I read it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx at Kingston University</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-kingston-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 18:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-kingston-university/</guid>
      <description>Last Monday 24th of November I delivered a small lecture about Libgdx at Kingston University of London. This complements Alberto&amp;rsquo;s Libgdx workshop at Cadiz University last week as part of a series of activities to promote Libgdx and our recently released book.
I talked about what Libgdx can offer developers as well as the advantages of using open source tools as opposed to proprietary technologies, especially when it comes to students.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
