<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Games development on David Saltares</title>
    <link>https://saltares.com/categories/games-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Games development on David Saltares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saltares.com/categories/games-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Doodle: a crazy drawing &amp; guessing game</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/doodle-a-crazy-drawing-guessing-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/doodle-a-crazy-drawing-guessing-game/</guid>
      <description>✏️ Introducing Doodle, a crazy drawing &amp;amp; guessing chain game. Think Pictionary meets Telephone. Better played with your friends over a video call!

🏠 Doodle is a little side project I made during covid-19 confinement to play with friends while we cannot meet face to face. Initially, I thought the crisis would end before I finished it, which would make me lose interest. Little did I know! Not only did I finish it, Doodle has already lightened up the mood in a few remote evenings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plague: a Godot Wild Jam 18 game postmortem</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/plague-a-godot-wild-jam-18-game-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/plague-a-godot-wild-jam-18-game-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, Jay Cano and I took part in the week-long Godot Wild Jam 18 and submitted Plague. Here are some of my personal thoughts on how we did and maybe some lessons for the future!
📈 Results Out of 43 submissions, we ranked 6th overall. That is the top 13th percentile. More importantly, we ranked 3th for fun or top 6th percentile. For the sake of comparison, Onederful Wizard, which we submitted to the GMTK 2019, ranked 294 out of 2617 entries (top 11th percentile).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Delivery pipeline for Godot and itch.io</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/continuous-delivery-pipeline-for-godot-and-itch.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/continuous-delivery-pipeline-for-godot-and-itch.io/</guid>
      <description>During the recent Godot Wild Jam 18, I implemented a full Continuous Delivery system to automatically publish Plague, our entry, on itch.io. The pipeline relies on Github Actions, the same mechanism I use to build and deploy this very blog.
Setting up your own is easy peasy and possibly free!
⚒️ Pipeline overview  Someone pushes to the master branch on the remote repo. The game is exported for all available platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plague - Godot Wild Jam 18</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/plague-godot-wild-jam-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 14:35:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/plague-godot-wild-jam-18/</guid>
      <description>My friend Jay and I recently took part in Godot Wild Jam, a week long game jam where entries must be made using Godot Engine.
We had an absolute blast! The result is Plague, a procedurally generated action platformer. You can play it in the browser and use either a gamepad or keyboard!
 .Get &#34;linkText&#34;    Don&amp;rsquo;t congratulate us on the visuals just yet, we used the Rogue Noir asset pack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run automated tests for your Godot game on CI</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/run-godot-tests-ci-travis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/run-godot-tests-ci-travis/</guid>
      <description>Automated testing in gamedev Nowadays, most people agree that automated testing is absolutely crucial for all software development. Not so much when it comes to games development though. I still believe that the games industry would be able to iterate and ship faster by introducing unit and integration testing in the right places.
Godot and Gut Butch Wesley appears to be onboard, considering he created Gut, an automated testing framework for the Godot Game Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ludum Dare 38 - Theme ideas</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/ludum-dare-38-theme-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 22:07:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/ludum-dare-38-theme-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Ludum Dare 38 starts in a couple of hours. This one is special as it marks the 15th anniversary of the biggest weekend game development friendly competition in the world!
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know about Ludum Dare and are interested, check the documentary they just released.
I was thinking of participating using Godot Engine. I have a couple of social compromises this weekend and, honestly, I am a bit scared of failing miserably, so I&amp;rsquo;m not too sure how far I&amp;rsquo;ll take this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Godot Engine out for the #godotjam</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/trying-godot-engine-out-for-the-godotjam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 11:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/trying-godot-engine-out-for-the-godotjam/</guid>
      <description>Godot Engine caught my eye a while back as a serious open source alternative to the ubiquitous Unity. Some of you may know I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with the Libgdx project for some time, I even wrote a book about it!
There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with Libgdx, I absolutely love the project and the more than welcoming community around it.
The problem is that shipping a game is hard. Doing so whilst working a full time job is harder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.7.3 released!</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-3-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 14:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-3-released/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a new Ashley release, check the changes for 1.7.3 below:
 API addition: Adds ‘createComponent()&amp;quot; method to Engine class. Commit 07fc2ba6bcd9996c472c651b56b57b32fd8fd3a7. API addition: Adds ‘createEntity()&amp;quot; method to Engine class. Commit 45dd7e0e4a52c8d65f520fac4e8f4e83471b215b. API addition: Adds ‘addAndReturn()&amp;quot; method to Entity class. Commit 423148a2719873efb50d4f2b3982c247df4fceca. Bug fix: Fixes systems going out of priority order after removal. Issue #237. Bug fix: Fixes returning pooled entity to the entity pool twice. Issue #221. Update: uses Travis for CI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-in console for Libgdx games</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/built-in-console-for-libgdx-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 16:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/built-in-console-for-libgdx-games/</guid>
      <description>A lot of games come with a built-in console that lets you enter commands, which is especially useful during development. Most times, it gets disabled before shipping although, occasionally, devs let you bring it up and enter cheat codes. CryEngine comes with a built-in console.
When you&amp;quot;re testing a new feature you just wrote, it can be incredibly useful to pause, reset the scene, teleport your character, become invincible, switch to a different level or even adjust some parameters in the AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2D vision system with Ashley and Box2D</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/2d-vision-system-with-ashley-and-box2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 16:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/2d-vision-system-with-ashley-and-box2d/</guid>
      <description>In Sloppynauts the player had to remain undetected, avoiding CCTV cameras and alien baddies. We constantly had to determine who could see who and whether the player was hidden behind something. We wrote a nice reusable system using Ashley and Box2D and I think it&amp;quot;d be a shame if it went to waste. So here it is in case you&amp;quot;d like to use it.
This 2D vision system is generic enough to work with both side-scrolling and top-down games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sloppynauts, our LibGDXJAM entry</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/sloppynauts-our-libgdxjam-entry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 23:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/sloppynauts-our-libgdxjam-entry/</guid>
      <description>After a crazy weekend before the deadline, we finally managed to put something playable together for LibGDXJAM.
We&amp;quot;d love you to have a go, and leave some feedback.
 We are definitely aware of the shortcomings of the game. We spent a lot of the jam working on a custom Overlap2D level loader and not so much on actual content, so you can actually finish the game in under a minute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.7.1 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 12:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-1-released/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a new Ashley release, check the changes for 1.7.1 below:
 API addition: expose IntervalSystem interval value (read-only). Bug fix: fixed pending entity operations not being processed in the right order. Bug fix: fixed adding component in empty family EntityListener causing wrong EntityListener calls. Bug fix: fixed some entity operations not being performed under special circumstances. Internals: split Engine internals into loosely coupled, single responsibility smaller classes. Update: uses Libgdx 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibGDXJAM update #3</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdxjam-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 11:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdxjam-update-3/</guid>
      <description>Oh my God, enter panic mode, just 8 days left until the #LibGDXJAM deadline! We&amp;rsquo;ve been hard at work, especially @DrillerDev who&amp;rsquo;s pushed the character design and animation.
Look at this bad boy for instance, better not to mess with his alien gun.
Or the beholder powered alien surveillance.
Please, ignore the placeholder environment art, it&amp;rsquo;s the textures from the Overlap2D example project. Our chubby astronaut can run, crouch, jump and push boxes around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibGDXJAM New Year&#39;s update</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdxjam-new-years-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 19:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdxjam-new-years-update/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;quot;re halfway through the #libGDXJAM and some work has been done between Christmas and New Year&amp;rsquo;s eve.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a few updates.
 @DrillerDev as joined us as an artist and has already produced some awesome concepts. Alberto and I have been working on an Overlap2D scene loader and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much working supporting a bunch of things: composites, textures, lights, physics and particles. We have a somewhat buggy physics based platformer movement system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibJDX jam is on: Life in Space</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libjdxjam-is-on-life-in-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 12:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libjdxjam-is-on-life-in-space/</guid>
      <description>Check the keynote and all the awkward moments from the dev team, including mine!
The theme is Life in Space and I&amp;quot;m teaming up with Alberto for #libGDXJAM and here&amp;rsquo;s our idea:
 Abe&amp;rsquo;s Oddysee meets This War of Mine meets Boogerman&amp;hellip; in space!
 A bunch of dangerously unprepared astronauts land on a strange planet only to find out it&amp;rsquo;s inhabited by big fat angry aliens with guns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on unit testing for Ashley and games in general</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/thoughts-on-unit-testing-for-ashley-and-games-in-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 15:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/thoughts-on-unit-testing-for-ashley-and-games-in-general/</guid>
      <description>Shortly after we moved Ashley into the Libgdx family, we started writing unit tests for every single component in the framework using jUnit.
Unit testing goodness That was over a year and a half ago and it has proven to be a huge win for many reasons.
 Issue reporters can (and should) include a test that breaks as a way of explaining the problem. We can then easily include it into the suite, fix it and prevent future regressions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.7.0 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 21:48:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-7-0-released/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a new Ashley release, check the changes for 1.7.0 below:
 API change: removed UUIDs from entities, users should implement their own ID system when needed. This helps with networked games. Update: components are added/removed immediately, listeners are notified after the current system finishes updating. Bug fix: fixed entity listeners not being called if a component is added inside another listener. Bug fix: does not allocate memory inside updateFamilyMembership(). Update: uses Libgdx 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Win a free digital copy of Libgdx Cookbook</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/win-a-free-digital-copy-of-libgdx-cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 12:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/win-a-free-digital-copy-of-libgdx-cookbook/</guid>
      <description>Update: the list of winners is available as a public draw. Congratulations and thanks for the support! The Libgdx Cookbook discount will continue until September the 30th. If you help us spread the word by retweeting the following message, you&amp;quot;ll have a chance of getting one of the three free digital copies of the book we&amp;quot;ll be giving away.
Libgdx Cookbook is 50% off, use the code: &amp;quot;LCPGDC50&amp;quot; and RT to enter a raffle for 3 digital copies of the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx Cookbook 50 off!</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-50-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 12:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-50-off/</guid>
      <description>Libgdx Cross-platform Game Development Cookbook is 50% off until September 30th if you get it from Packt&amp;rsquo;s website using the code LCPGDC50. You have to admit it&amp;rsquo;s a total steal, considering it&amp;rsquo;s the most complete and up to date Libgdx book out there.
 Over 75 to-the-point articles that will show you how to leverage a particular aspect of Libgdx for your game. Every article is accompanied by a runnable sample available on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.6.0 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-6-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 22:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-6-0-released/</guid>
      <description>A new Ashley package has shipped, making 1.6.0 the latest stable version. Here&amp;rsquo;s the summary of the changes:
 API change: Component is now an interface. API addition: adds getEngine() to EntitySystem. API addition: EntityListeners now are notified by priority order. API consistency: defines what happens when an Entity is added twice to an Engine and when we try do nested updates. We throw an exception in both cases. API consistency: adding an EntitySystem of the same class twice replaces the previous one, just like it has always happened when adding Components to an Entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx at Intel Buzz Workshop Stockholm 2015: pictures and video</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-intel-buzz-workshop-stockholm-2015-pictures-and-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 21:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-intel-buzz-workshop-stockholm-2015-pictures-and-video/</guid>
      <description>As I recently mentioned, a couple of weeks ago I flew to Stockholm to attend the Intel Buzz Workshop, a conference focused on mobile games development where I preached the perks of Libgdx. The event had a great turnout and my talk seemed to have been well received. Moreover, I also got to meet cool people IRL such as Adrian, the guy behind the Artemis ECS.
For those who missed it and would like to watch me ramble about how brilliant Libgdx is for a whole 20 minutes, here is the video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx at Intel Buzz Workshop Stockholm 2015</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-intel-buzz-workshop-stockholm-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 21:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-intel-buzz-workshop-stockholm-2015/</guid>
      <description>Quick update to let you know I have been invited to talk about all Libgdx things at Intel Buzz Workshop 2015, which will take place in Stockholm on July 17th. It will be a one day conference on mobile games development and will feature talks on virtual reality, Unreal Engine 4 and lots of cool stuff, check the programme for more details.
Register if you are interested, tickets are free until July 6th!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx Cookbook samples updated to support Libgdx 1.6.0</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-samples-updated-to-support-libgdx-1-6-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 11:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-samples-updated-to-support-libgdx-1-6-0/</guid>
      <description>Haven&amp;rsquo;t bought Libgdx Cross-platform Game Development Cookbook yet? Stop reading and go get it!
Quick update to inform you that I just updated the samples repository to use Libgdx 1.6.0 and Ashley 1.5.0, both recently released.
Libgdx 1.6.0 introduces changes in our font rendering API, which require a few minor tweaks to the framework calls, nothing major.
7 months after the release of the book, we continue to support it. Rest assured, it is the most up to date Libgdx publication at this point in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.5.0 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-5-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 10:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-5-0-released/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the contributors, here&amp;rsquo;s a new version of Ashley, which now stands at 1.5.0. A new version of your favorite component based entity framework is out.
The version comes with a bunch of bug fixes that, hopefully, will iron out some of the rough edges in Ashley.
 API addition: adds getFamily() method to IntervalIteratingSystem and IteratingSystem. API change: IntervalSystem‘s update() method is now final, as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to override it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx Cookbook samples updated</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-samples-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 23:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-samples-updated/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months since Libgdx Cross-platform Game Development Cookbook came out. Quite a few things have happened since then in the Libgdx world, libraries are updated and some things break over time.
As promised, we have updated our samples repository to use the latest versions of Libgdx (1.5.5), Ashley (1.4.0), gdx-ai (1.5.0) and RoboVM (1.0.0) among others. Luckily enough, only a few changes were necessary to make everything work again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.4.0 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-4-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 16:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-4-0-released/</guid>
      <description>A new version of Ashley, your favourite component based entity framework is out. The 1.4.0 version comes with a bunch of bug fixes that, hopefully, will iron out some of the rough edges in Ashley.
 API deprecation: finallt removed the Family.getFor() methods. In order to retrieve a family, you can do Family.all().one().exclude().get(). API change: makes family Builder package protected. Bug fix: EntityOperation and ComponentOperation are now properly reset when put back into their pools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx at the LJC: slides and video</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-the-ljc-slides-video-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 21:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-the-ljc-slides-video-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I had the pleasure to deliver a talk about Libgdx at the London Java Community Meetup. To my surprise, there was a pretty decent turnout. The audience was lovely, seemed engaged and asked quite a few questions. No awkward silence at the end.
 Woohoo!
 Thanks a lot to everyone who attended, and to the organisers who made it possible. We must catch up next time at the pub afterwards!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.3.3 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/ashley-1-3-3-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 11:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/ashley-1-3-3-released/</guid>
      <description>As you can see, Ashley development has slowed down a bit. I would like to think it&amp;rsquo;s because we have a feature rich and stable framework rather than people having lost interest! Anyhow, there&amp;rsquo;s still been quite a bit of progress, enough to warrant a new release.
Ashley 1.3.3 is now out.
 API addition: added getEntity() method to Engine, it is now possible to retrieve entities by their ID. This will ease networked entity systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx at Kingston University</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-kingston-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 18:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-at-kingston-university/</guid>
      <description>Last Monday 24th of November I delivered a small lecture about Libgdx at Kingston University of London. This complements Alberto&amp;rsquo;s Libgdx workshop at Cadiz University last week as part of a series of activities to promote Libgdx and our recently released book.
I talked about what Libgdx can offer developers as well as the advantages of using open source tools as opposed to proprietary technologies, especially when it comes to students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx workshop at Cadiz University</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-workshop-at-cadiz-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 20:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-workshop-at-cadiz-university/</guid>
      <description>Alberto Cejas, colleague and co-author of Libgdx Cross-platform Game Development Cookbook delivered a Libgdx workshop at Cadiz University (Spain) last Friday 21st of November.
During a 2 hour session, the students put together a bunch of pieces to build Flappy Plane, a Flappy Bird clone originally developed by Mario Zechner. Moreover, there was free stuff! Alberto did a small raffle and gave two copies of our book away.
We&amp;rsquo;re really happy with the turnout, just take a look at the gallery below!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.3.2 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/ashley-1-3-2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 22:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/ashley-1-3-2-released/</guid>
      <description>More features, bug fixes and improvements for Ashley entity framework on this new release.
 API addition: we now use a builder pattern to create Family objects. More about it on the wiki. API addition: new SortedIteratingSystem by Lusito. API addition: now ImmutableArray implements the Iterable interface, which makes it a lot easier to iterate over entity collections. Bug fix: avoid double entity removal by accident. Bug fix: fixes StackOverflowError when processing entity operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx for Cross-platform Game Development Cookbook is out!</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/general/libgdx-for-cross-platform-game-development-cookbook-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 08:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/general/libgdx-for-cross-platform-game-development-cookbook-is-out/</guid>
      <description>After over a year of long hours after my day job, sweat, blood and tears, my colleague Alberto Cejas and I are extremely proud to announce that our Libgdx for Cross-platform Game Development Cookbook has finally been published.
The cookbook has over 75 practical recipes on how to get stuff done with Libgdx. It covers pretty much everything: graphics, input, audio, physics, maps, deployment and third-party extensions among many, many more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.3.1 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-3-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 21:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-3-1-released/</guid>
      <description>Small stability release for Ashley entity framework this time.
Bug fix: fixed IllegalArgumentException thrown when trying to remove components from an already reset entity. The call has no effect now. Thanks for that SgtCoDFish.
Bug fix: fixed family match failure due to silly silly hashing.
Bug fix: fixed entity.getId() always returning `` for recycled pooled entities.
Bug fix: fixed nested iteration problem caused by adding/removing entities from an entity added/removed listener handler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.3.0 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-3-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 20:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-3-0-released/</guid>
      <description>Time for another Ashley entity framework release! This time, the focus has been on stability by getting rid of as many bugs as we could find. Check all the new goodies below.
 API addition: adds IntervalSystem and IntervalIteratingSystem, which are updated at a fixed interval. API addition: adds getEntities() to IteratingSystem and IntervalIteratingSystem. API change: entities use long as ID. Changes entity.getIndex() for entity.getId(). Ids are reset to 0 after the entity is removed from the engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx Cookbook Git repository evolution</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-git-repository-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 15:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/libgdx-cookbook-git-repository-evolution/</guid>
      <description>As I have mentioned before, I have been working on a book titled Libgdx Cross-platform Game Development Cookbook, which is set to be released next month.
Me and my co-author Alberto used a Git repository throughout the text and sample code development process. Using Gource, I have created a video that illustrates the repository&amp;rsquo;s evolution. Neat, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?
  For those interested, here are the options I used.
gource -1280x720 --seconds-per-day 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.2.0 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-2-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 20:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-2-0-released/</guid>
      <description>There have been quite a few things happening in Ashley during the past month, enough to call for a brand new release. Ashley 1.2.0 can now be fetched from Maven Central and this is what you&amp;rsquo;ll find new.
 API addition: people requested to put Entity#getComponent(Class) back in, so we accepted SgtCODFish‘s PR. ComponentMapper is still the most efficient and encouraged method to retrieve an entity&amp;rsquo;s components. API addition: added PooledEngine#clearPools() to delete unused entity and component pool memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.1.0 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-1-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 17:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-1-1-0-released/</guid>
      <description>Just under a month of the first official release we are ready to release a new stable version: Ashley 1.1.0. Here is the list of changes.
 Performance improvements: massive performance gains with O(1) component retrieval through ComponentMapper and the use of Array&amp;lt;Entity&amp;gt; rather than IntMap&amp;lt;Entity&amp;gt;. Unfortunately this changes the API slightly, but hopefully you guys will appreciate the benefits. Complete Ashley manual: now the wiki has a lot more content, it fully covers Ashley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally, Ashley has a logo</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/finally-ashley-has-a-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 21:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/finally-ashley-has-a-logo/</guid>
      <description>Ashley now has a logo and it&amp;rsquo;s awesome! What an amazing contribution.
This is really good news because Ashley lacked an image to make it a bit more memorable. Now back to work, there will soon be a new release. Despite it involving some API changes, it will make for a much faster framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley javadocs and wiki</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-javadocs-and-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 06:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/projects/ashley-javadocs-and-wiki/</guid>
      <description>Ashley, your favourite entity framework now has online javadocs and a wiki.
 Wooohooo!
 The javadocs correspond to the latest repository snapshot. Our Jenkins instance grabs the code, runs the tests, builds the jars and publishes the javadocs to the badlogic.com server. Kudos to Mario for the setup.
I just started putting stuff into the wiki yesterday so it&amp;rsquo;s pretty empty as of now. Expect more content soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx setup tool now supports Ashley</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-setup-tool-now-supports-ashley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 18:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-setup-tool-now-supports-ashley/</guid>
      <description>Last night I added Ashley support to the official Libgdx setup tool. Creating Libgdx projects that use Ashley entity framework is now even easier. Simply make sure you tick the Ashley checkbox before generating your project.
By the way, if you already have a a project, adding the extra dependency is also trivial.
 Core project: com.badlogicgames.ashley:ashley:1.0.1 Android project: com.badlogicgames.ashley:ashley:1.0.1 GWT project: com.badlogicgames.ashley:ashley:1.0.1:sources  Remember that using Ashley in non Libgdx projects is also perfectly fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley 1.0.1 released</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/ashley-1-0-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 20:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/ashley-1-0-1-released/</guid>
      <description>Finally! During the past couple of months me and a bunch of awesome collaborators have been working on a proper Ashley release and now it&amp;rsquo;s done. Here is the list of the new shiny features.
Mind that some of them break the previous API. However, this is our first official release, we&amp;rsquo;ll push hard to keep the API backwards compatible from now on.
 Gradle: we got rid of the Eclipse projects and now use Gradle to manage our dependencies and build process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley entity framework</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/ashley-entity-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 19:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/ashley-entity-framework/</guid>
      <description>Loads of stuff in the pipeline lately: new job, finishing my book and some Ashley development. What? You don&amp;rsquo;t know what Ashley is? Here is a brief, straight from GitHub.
 A tiny entity framework written in Java. It&amp;rsquo;s inspired by frameworks like Ash (hence the name) and Artemis. Ashley tries to be a high-performance entity framework without the use of black-magic and thus making the API easy and transparent to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ludum Dare #29: Beneath the surface</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/ludum-dare-29-beneath-the-surface/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 15:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/ludum-dare-29-beneath-the-surface/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned here a few days ago, last weekend I entered the 29th edition of the Ludum Dare game jam, which had Beneath the surface as a theme. To be completely honest, I was only bothered to work on the project for about 4 hours each day. That probably explains why is my worst game jam entry so far.
Beneath the surface is a very simple, classic text adventure where the player needs to escape an underground cave by using commands in the form of verb object like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ludum Dare #29: I&#39;m in!</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/ludum-dare-29-im-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 19:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/ludum-dare-29-im-in/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m up for Ludum Dare despite not being too sure about whether or not I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to invest enough time on it. The last couple of editions eluded me, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to miss yet another one.
Given the time constraints, I might even go for just a text adventure. Or maybe not, who knows. I&amp;rsquo;ll decide in the morning, once the theme is announced!
Tools of the trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Castilla: La Mancha University talk</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/castilla-la-mancha-university-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 08:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/castilla-la-mancha-university-talk/</guid>
      <description>Oh $deity, it is hard to be back after a 5 day break! Following a healing long weekend in Madrid, yesterday I went over to Ciudad Real to deliver my presentation titled &amp;ldquo;How to break into the Games Industry with Open Source Software&amp;rdquo; at the engineering university school.
I would dare to say it was well received. A zero total count of rotten tomatoes thrown at me shall be good enough of an indicator to back up my previous statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libgdx has &gt;1M LoC project</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-is-a-1m-loc-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2014 17:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/libgdx-is-a-1m-loc-project/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t exactly remember how, but last night I came across Code Analyzer, an open source Java desktop utility that counts lines of code. Out of curiosity, I downloaded the runnable jar file and tried it with Libgdx.
I was very much aware that Libgdx was a pretty big project but certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t expect it to be that large. At the time of writing the HEAD of the repository contains 1.048.646 lines of Java, C and C++.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute back to open source projects</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/computing/contribute-back-to-open-source-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 16:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/computing/contribute-back-to-open-source-projects/</guid>
      <description>Developers love Libgdx, it&amp;rsquo;s an extremely efficient, easy to use, open source, feature rich, cross platform framework. It has a huge community, and a very active repository. What&amp;rsquo;s not to love? The fact that 1.40% apps on AppBrain use Libgdx backs that up.
Have you thought about contributing back?
 Who, me?
 Yes and here&amp;rsquo;s why.
So much win The beauty of a healthy community driven project such as Libgdx is that decisions are crowd-sourced and code is always peer reviewed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix your timestep in Libgdx and Box2D</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/fixing-your-timestep-in-libgdx-and-box2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 18:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/fixing-your-timestep-in-libgdx-and-box2d/</guid>
      <description>Fix your Timestep is a fantastic article by Glenn Fiedler that explains the different ways to tick a physics simulation. Show some self-respect, go read it and check some of his other articles on physics and network code. Some might be 8 years old but still totally relevant.
Essentially, it covers different approaches to pick a delta value to pass through to the physics engine along their strengths and weaknesses. The topic is complex but has an undeniable impact on games&#39; behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SionCore, a small game engine</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/sioncore-a-small-game-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 23:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/sioncore-a-small-game-engine/</guid>
      <description>Today I created a repository on Gihub to keep track of my code base and I named it SionCore. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t made overnight, it&amp;rsquo;s the result of several small game projects, such as game jam gigs and Math Maze.
Slowly, it became obvious that some components were highly reusable and game agnostic. That is why I thought it would be good to make it public.
Who knows, maybe someday someone might even contribute!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Maze postmortem</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/games/math-maze-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 19:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/games/math-maze-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>After approximately 5 months of work, Math Maze went live on Google Play on September the 2nd, so I thought a little postmortem was in order. For those who are not aware, Math Maze is a very simple brain teaser math based game.
The player has to move a purple block across a labyrinth towards the exit. However, there are numerical conditions blocking the way. In order to traverse them, the purple block has to combine itself with operations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
