<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game jams on David Saltares</title>
    <link>https://saltares.com/game-jams/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game jams on David Saltares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saltares.com/game-jams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Plague</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/game-jams/plague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/game-jams/plague/</guid>
      <description>.Get &#34;linkText&#34;    The world has turned into a very dark place. First, dangerous electric storms fall from the sky. But now&amp;hellip; demons from hell plague the earth. All hope is lost.
However, you refuse to give up and will put up a fight for as long as you can!
🎮 The game Plague is an infinite action platformer with procedurally generated levels. It&amp;rsquo;s got gamepad support and you can play it from your browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onederful Wizard</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/game-jams/onederful-wizzard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/game-jams/onederful-wizzard/</guid>
      <description>.Get &#34;linkText&#34;    Onederful Wizard is a puzzle action game where a little wizard goes from room to room defeating monsters with a single fireball.
The theme of the game jam was &amp;ldquo;Only One&amp;rdquo;, so we created a game where you have only one shot to solve all the puzzles and defeat all the enemies. After casting the spell, you will have to go a fetch it again so you can keep going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sloppynauts</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/game-jams/sloppynauts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 22:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/game-jams/sloppynauts/</guid>
      <description>Sloppynauts is a 2D stealth platformer game where the player controls a chubby astronaut who must escape a dangerous alien planet undetected.
 Game Jam: LibGDXJAM 2015-2016 Development time: 1 month Technology: Java, LibGDX and Ashley Team: @DrillerDev, @omniyo and @d_saltares Download: game, source code  Screenshots    Sloppynauts 1
      Sloppynauts 2
      Sloppynauts 3
      Sloppynauts 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beneath the surface</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/game-jams/beneath-the-surface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 22:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/game-jams/beneath-the-surface/</guid>
      <description>Beneath the surface is a very simple, classic text adventure where the player needs to escape an underground cave by using commands in the form of verb + object.
 Open door
  Game Jam: Ludum Dare #29 Development time: 48h compo Technology: Java using libgdx and Universal Tween Engine Download: desktop, source code  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightbyrinth</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/game-jams/lightbyrinth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 22:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/game-jams/lightbyrinth/</guid>
      <description>Lightbyrinth is a top down light based maze. You control a blue sphere that has to find the exit in each level while avoiding the randomly spawned red spheres.
 Game Jam: Ludum Dare #26 Development time: 48h compo Technology: Java using libgdx and box2dlights Download: browser, desktop, source  Screenshots    Lightbyrinth 1
      Lightbyrinth 2
      Lightbyrinth 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/game-jams/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 21:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/game-jams/evolution/</guid>
      <description>Evolution is a side scroller action platformer starred by a caveman who has to endure all sorts of dangers and get to the goal.
 Game Jam: Ludum Dare #24 Development time: 48h compo Technology: Java using libgdx Download: desktop, source code  Screenshots    Evolution caveman 01
      Evolution caveman 02
      Evolution caveman 03
                             </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
