<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology strategy on David Saltares</title>
    <link>https://saltares.com/series/technology-strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology strategy on David Saltares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saltares.com/series/technology-strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>4 steps to create a solid technology strategy</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/4-steps-to-create-a-solid-technology-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/4-steps-to-create-a-solid-technology-strategy/</guid>
      <description>By Anastasia Petrova on Unsplash As an Engineering leader, you want to create a solid technology strategy to provide the context your team needs to make excellent decisions. But how should you go about it?
📚 1. Gather context Most of the difficulty resides in identifying and reflecting on the context of the business and your team. Once you do that, you will realise that actually writing a strategy doc is the easy part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of solid technology strategy and principles</title>
      <link>https://saltares.com/the-importance-of-solid-technology-strategy-and-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saltares.com/the-importance-of-solid-technology-strategy-and-principles/</guid>
      <description>By Nick on Unsplash A solid technology strategy is a requirement for building a high-performing engineering organisation that consistently hits business goals. To better understand the importance of technology strategy, we can look at what happens to teams that don’t have one.
It is pretty standard for poor engineering leaders not to have a technology strategy written down and shared with the entire organisation.
Engineering leaders don’t need to think about strategy, and they can come up with a different one every day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
